<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>La Tinaja</title>
<description>My name is Brian Jones. These are my notes on topics including books, publishing, tech, and history.</description>
<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
<atom:link href="http://tinaja.computer/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Extracting Substrings from URLs with Alfred Workflows</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I frequently find myself needing to extract a predictable piece of data from a URL, like a product id, for pasting into a file or database as metadata that might be used to contact an API or construct cleaned-up URLs in the future. The predictable formatting of the part of the URL that I care about makes this the kind of task that perfectly lends itself to simple automation, saving me the small friction of manually editing these URLs in place.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.alfredapp.com/workflows/">Alfred workflows</a> are a quick way to run this category of automation. Because the data is in a URL, I’m typically copying the URL from my web browser to the clipboard and pasting it into a text editor or field. With an Alfred workflow, I can run a script on the text from the clipboard and put my desired result back on the clipboard, cleaned up and ready to paste wherever I’d like.</p>

<p>I have several workflows that fit this general use case, and my interaction with all of them follows the following pattern:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Me:</strong> Copy my starting text to the clipboard</li>
  <li><strong>Me:</strong> Invoke the workflow with an Alfred keyword
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Alfred:</strong> Grab the contents of the clipboard</li>
      <li><strong>Alfred:</strong> Run a short Python script on that data</li>
      <li><strong>Alfred:</strong> Copy the result of the script back to the clipboard</li>
      <li><em>(optionally)</em> <strong>Alfred:</strong> Paste the result of the script to the currently active window</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Me:</strong> Paste the text now in the clipboard where I want it if I haven’t already allowed Alfred to do it for me</li>
</ul>

<p>To take a specific example, we can walk through building a workflow to extract the OCLC number for an edition of a book from a <a href="http://worldcat.org">Worldcat.org</a> URL.</p>

<hr />

<p>A typical URL for a book on Worldcat.org reached through their onsite search might look like the following:</p>

<p><code class="highlighter-rouge">http://www.worldcat.org/title/history-and-gis-epistemologies-considerations-and-reflections/oclc/910980341&amp;referer=brief_results</code></p>

<p>The only part I care about are the numerals between <code class="highlighter-rouge">/oclc/</code> and the <code class="highlighter-rouge">&amp;</code> (in this case, <code class="highlighter-rouge">910980341</code>). With that unique identifier I can construct my own tidier Worldcat.org URLs later or use their API in a script.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="/images/2017/OCLC-workflow-overview.jpg" alt="Complete Alfred Workflow Screenshot" /></p>

<p>The screenshot above shows the final layout of the workflow. Assuming we have the URL on the clipboard, the workflow performs the following actions:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Launch when invoked with the keyword <code class="highlighter-rouge">oclc</code> from Alfred</li>
  <li>Grab the clipboard contents with a bash script</li>
  <li>Take those contents and match them against a simple regular expression (in this case in a Python script)</li>
  <li>Copy to the clipboard and paste in the front most app</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="1-launch">1. Launch</h3>

<p><img src="/images/2017/OCLC-1-launch.jpg" alt="Launch Settings" /></p>

<p>In the Alfred workflow editor, create a new ‘Input’ of the ‘Keyword’ type, select the keyword you would like to use to invoke your workflow, and give it a descriptive title.</p>

<h3 id="2-grab-clipboard">2. Grab Clipboard</h3>

<p>Link your ‘Keyword’ input to a new ’Action’ of type ’Run Script’. You can leave all of the sets for this script alone; the default language choice, <code class="highlighter-rouge">/bin/bash</code>, is what we want in this case. Our script will be a single bash command to grab the contents of the clipboard.</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><pre class="highlight"><code>pbpaste
</code></pre>
</div>

<h3 id="3-find-oclc">3. Find OCLC</h3>

<p>Link your <code class="highlighter-rouge">/bin/bash</code> ‘Run Script’ action to a new ’Action’ of type ’Run Script’. This time we will want to change our settings for the Language to <code class="highlighter-rouge">/usr/bin/python</code>. (All we’re doing is matching a regular expression which would be possible using any of the language options. I just like Python.)</p>

<p>The script is simple. We take the input from our bash script that grabbed the clipboard contents and we match it against a regular expression that essentially says “Give me the run of numerals that follow the string <code class="highlighter-rouge">/oclc/</code> in the provided text.” Finally, we write our result to standard output which is how our next Alfred action will receive it.</p>

<div class="language-python highlighter-rouge"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kn">import</span> <span class="nn">re</span>
<span class="kn">import</span> <span class="nn">sys</span>

<span class="n">url</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s">"{query}"</span>

<span class="n">matchObj</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">re</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">search</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">r'/oclc/([0-9]*)'</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">url</span><span class="p">)</span>

<span class="n">sys</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">stdout</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">write</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">matchObj</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">group</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">))</span>
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>A couple of things to note:</p>

<ol>
  <li><code class="highlighter-rouge"><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">query</span><span class="p">}</span></code> is a placeholder Alfred looks for in our script in order to insert whatever string of data is coming from the previous action in our workflow. It is not a standard piece of Python syntax.</li>
  <li>A ‘regular expression’ is a string of characters that defines a pattern of text. In the case of the above script, it is the part that reads <code class="highlighter-rouge">/oclc/([0-9]*)</code>, but they can be far more complex. For a good introduction to using regular expressions, you can look at the Google lesson on <a href="https://developers.google.com/edu/python/regular-expressions">Python Regular Expressions</a>.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="4-output">4. Output</h3>

<p><img src="/images/2017/OCLC-4-output.jpg" alt="Output Settings" /></p>

<p>Finally, we just want to link a new ‘Output’ of type ‘Copy to Clipboard’ and use the default content which is just to pass through the input from our Python script. Depending on the context, we could do additional formatting here by editing the text around <code class="highlighter-rouge"><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">query</span><span class="p">}</span></code>.</p>

<p>In this case, I have also checked the box to ‘Automatically paste to front most app’ because that matches my needs the vast majority of the time I’m using this particular workflow, but in some cases it may be preferable to leave the result on the clipboard without automatically pasting.</p>

<hr />

<p>That’s it. This approach can be repeated for any number of small extraction tasks—to take ASIN numbers from Amazon.com product links in order to construct affiliate links, for example.</p>

<p>Any single instance of this task would be trivial to perform manually, but Alfred’s ability to combine interaction with the clipboard and access to a scripting language with nice regular expression support triggered through a quick-launch command kills the tedious friction of repeat manual editing and becomes second nature.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 11:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/03/URL-substring-alfred-workflows.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/07/03/URL-substring-alfred-workflows.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Zodiacs, Hackers, and Geography</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B004IATCES/ref=nosim/latin031-20">John Sandford. <i>The Fool’s Run</i>. New York: Berkley Books, 1989.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>A late 80s techno-thriller with a painter-hacker protagonist who has to explain personal computing fundamentals to his partners on a corporate espionage gig. A decent page-turner that is the first in a series on which I plan to follow through.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/988526544">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B004IATCES/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0674066480/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Sean Roberts. <i>Printing a Mediterranean World: Florence, Constantinople, and the Renaissance of Geography</i>. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press, 2013.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Roberts uses the gift of a printed edition of a late fifteenth-century Florentine geography to two Ottoman rulers as a jumping off point to explore the ‘rediscovery’ of geography and the materiality of knowledge and exchange in the late medieval and early modern Mediterranean world. He expands on the existing trend in complicating the supposedly transformative and modernizing effects taof the reintroduction of Ptolemy’s <em>Geography</em> into European intellectual life, but his primary contribution is in exploring the specific material characteristics of the book in question to identify the local peculiarities of commerce, geopolitics, and religion that shaped a Mediterranean world traditionally presumed to be aggressively transnational and multicultural.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/900039945">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0674066480/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B008UX8SNU/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Neal Stephenson. <i>Zodiac</i>. New York: Bantam Books, 1988.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p><em>Zodiac</em> was only Stephenson’s second novel, and it is interesting to read something with his voice in which some of his more idiosyncratic qualities (long technical digressions, large-scale world-building at the expense of plotting, etc.) have yet to develop. It’s a relatively short and tight thriller about corporate corruption and ecopolitics with a late 80s Generation-X-y tone that is evocative of the era.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/678839423">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B008UX8SNU/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 10:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/01/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/07/01/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Sean Roberts on the Materiality of Books</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>What we can learn about books and their relationship to the ideas they supposedly contain has everything to do with the ways in which people interacted with them and the ways in which books conditioned those interactions. In short, another way of asking what we can learn from books might be to ask <em>how</em> we learn from books. At a moment when so many of us are moving ever more rapidly away from “hard copies” and embracing eBooks of all varieties, it is worth remembering that the material properties of books long set important conditions for their reading. Indeed, even the electronic simulacra to which we now find ourselves accustomed imitate physical acts like turning pages, inserting ribbons, and dog-earing corners. Virtual book collections take on the appearance of wooden shelves and follow organizational schemes derived from physical libraries. All such mimicry, of course, comes at great expense both to processing resources and programming hours. Yet it is deemed indispensable because reading remains a stubbornly material act.</p>

  <p>– <cite>Sean Roberts, <a href="http://www.worldcat.org/title/printing-a-mediterranean-world-florence-constantinople-and-the-renaissance-of-geography/oclc/900039945">Printing a Mediterranean World: Florence, Constantinople, and the Renaissance of Geography</a>, p. 175.</cite></p>
</blockquote>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 22:13:01 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/26/roberts-on-materiality-of-books.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/06/26/roberts-on-materiality-of-books.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Mario, Garbage, and Computational Abundance</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01H2KDZ7A/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Alyse Knorr. <i>Super Mario Bros. 3</i>. Los Angeles, CA: Boss Fight Books, 2016.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is another entry in the Boss Fight Books series that is as much personal memoir as exploration of the game itself. Knorr interrogates gamer nostalgia through a thorough analysis of the game mechanics and level design of Super Mario Bros. 3 in the context of the widely held consensus that is a great, if not the greatest, platform game ever made. Along the way, her own nostalgia for childhood family interactions around the game adds an additional layer to the contingent nature of media experience.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/951476372">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01H2KDZ7A/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B011JAV030/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Sarah Jeong. <i>The Internet of Garbage</i>. New York: Forbes Media, 2015.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Jeong has done a great job making the case both for the importance of community moderation online and in explaining how that work is much more nuanced than blocking, deleting, and banning.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B011JAV030/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00D97HPQI/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Erik Brynjolfsson and Andrew McAfee. <i>The Second Machine Age: Work, Progress, and Prosperity in a Time of Brilliant Technologies</i>. New York: W.W. Norton & Company, 2014.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>In this readable account, Brynjolfsson and McAfee outline some of the tensions between conventional economic wisdom and new realities of labor and markets in an age of computational abundance. While not discounting the looming hardships for many workers, they are generally sanguine about the continued need for human labor provided that training is geared to maximizing those human strengths for which machines can serve only as complements, rather than substitutes. As with so many business books, the historical foundations of some of their arguments make their shallow approach to historiography a bit disappointing. The work’s strength comes from the pair’s clear explication of policy prescriptions from their analysis.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/960056027">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00D97HPQI/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1118987241/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Brad Williams, David Damstra, and Hal Stern. <i>Professional WordPress: Design and Development</i>. Indianapolis, IN: Wrox, 2015.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Having never done more than hacked together limited rough-and-ready custom one-off changes to WordPress themes, I felt like I need a good A-Z overview of the world of WordPress development as a foundation for a project I’m working on. Spending a week or so with this book following a single path orchestrated by a constant and consistent author saved me a lot of the time and confusion I’ve been wasting on abortive strolls through developer blogs and howtos over the last few months.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/913971983">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1118987241/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 15:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/06/21/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/06/21/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Rebecca Solnit on Privilege and Obliviousness</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>This is why I always pair privilege with obliviousness; obliviousness is privilege’s form of deprivation. When you don’t hear others, you don’t imagine them, they become unreal, and you are left in the wasteland of a world with only yourself in it, and that surely makes you starving, though you know not for what, if you have ceased to imagine others exist in any true deep way that matters. This is about a need for which we hardly have language or at least not a familiar conversation.</p>

  <p>– <cite>Rebecca Solnit, <a href="http://lithub.com/rebecca-solnit-the-loneliness-of-donald-trump/">The Loneliness of Donald Trump</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 07:23:01 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/31/solnit-on-privilege.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/31/solnit-on-privilege.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Bohemian Grove, Post-Scarcity Utopia, and Web Apps</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <h3 id="links">Links</h3>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/05/15/richard-russells-xl-recordings-empire?mbid=nl_170512_Daily"><strong>Richard Russell’s XL Recording Empire—The New Yorker—Matthew Trammell</strong></a>: Part personal profile and part business analysis, this recent magazine piece from <em>The New Yorker</em> was most interesting for me in its treatment of the important role Russell’s taste and opinionated selectivity has played in making XL a success. Being particular does not necessarily need to mean niche.</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2017/5/22/15673712/anker-battery-charger-amazon-empire-steven-yang-interview"><strong>How Anker is Beating Apple and Samsung at Their Own Accessory Game—The Verge—Nick Statt</strong></a>: This interview and profile of Anker founder Steven Yang makes a nice complement to the Russell piece. Anker’s current challenge is to grow out of a niche to a more general product company while maintaining their reputation for qualit</li>
</ul>


    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00U5MMZ2E/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Tracy Osborn. <i>Hello Web App: Learn How to Build a Web App</i>. San Jose, CA: Self-published, 2015.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Osborn selects an interesting framing for her <em>Hello Web App</em> books: sharing only the minimum necessary information to get a web application up and running in a browser with limited programming experience and essentially no computer science fundamentals. The first of these two books provides a kind of paint-by-numbers template for building a simple Django CRUD application in Python.  Having learned by this sort of trial and error herself, Osborn has a good sense of what is necessary and in what order for the beginner to get a satisfying, tangible project up and running as quickly as possible. However, Osborn necessarily makes some assumptions in how she will limit her scope in order to keep things beginner-friendly, and it will take a certain kind of learner to feel free in breaking those assumptions and making their own experimentations when it comes time to grow beyond this template.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/957188874">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00U5MMZ2E/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01LXOO7UQ/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jon Ronson. <i>The Elephant in the Room: A Journey into the Trump Campaign and the “Alt-Right”</i>. Seattle, WA: Amazon Kindle Single, 2016.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I bought this Kindle Single a couple of weeks after the election last fall, but have only now gotten around to reading it. I’ve always had something of a <a href="https://twitter.com/jonesbp/status/860151673637011458">soft spot</a> for Alex Jones despite his becoming a less benign force in the world these days—perhaps he never was benign after all—and Jones’s career-making Bohemian Grove documentary was actually the result of a lark proposed by Ronson. As a result, Ronson’s more personal, and even sympathetic, treatment of Jones as both a person and character appeals to me as being truer than the wholesale condemnation that is more typical of this moment. It also means that Ronson was able to get access to some backstage conversations between Jones, his crew, and associates like Roger Stone that are batshit crazy and fascinating.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01LXOO7UQ/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01774NMEW/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Tracy Osborn. <i>Hello Web App: Intermediate Concepts</i>. San Jose, CA: Self-published, 2015.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p><em>Hello Web App: Intermediate Concepts</em> is the second in a series of books introducing novice developers to building a web app with Django. Where the first installment provides a walkthrough for building a CRUD app from start to finish, the second book is more of a recipe book for specific features: a messaging system or Stripe integration, for example. The examples are helpful and include functionality that almost any web app project will require, but the shift in approach will mean that true novices should spend some time working on whatever they’ve based on their time with the first book before looking to this one for features to add. There is not enough to the demonstration project in the first book to support adding most of these features as anything other than demonstrations.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/952566688">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01774NMEW/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01FQQ47OC/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Cory Doctorow. <i>Walkaway: A Novel</i>. New York: Tom Doherty Associates, 2017.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Most Cory Doctorow novels work better for me as ‘idea novels’ than as stories in themselves. His tendency to have characters break into multi-paragraph monologues outlining the political ramifications of some aspect of maker culture or copy protection almost never serves the pacing of his plots well. However, I read all of them and am always compelled by at least some part of them to think about something new. <em>Walkaway</em> was perhaps the most Doctorow-ish of novels in both these good and bad senses. I read it relatively quickly and mostly enjoyed myself most of the time, but having finished I may remember my ambivalence above another sensation of reading it.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/975270622">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01FQQ47OC/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 09:53:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/24/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/24/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Uber, Airbnb, and Murder</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062341650/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Dorothy L. Sayers. <i>Murder Must Advertise</i>. New York: Bourbon Street Books, 2014 [1933].</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The first of the Lord Wolsey mysteries I’ve read—this one has him undercover as a copy writer to investigate a suspicious death at an advertising firm. There are clear Wodehousian influences in Sayers’s treatment of her protagonist, and the mystery itself unfolded nicely. From a historical perspective the social commentary on advertising, recreational drug use, and consumerism was interesting.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/902745527">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062341650/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0316388394/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Brad Stone. <i>The Upstarts: How Uber, Airbnb and the Killer Companies of the New Silicon Valley are Changing the World</i>. New York: Little, Brown and Company, 2017.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>It can be easy to get into patterns of knee jerk rejection of these businesses, particularly Uber, with the stories in the news about the labor and housing problems caused by these business models. I think Stone is fundamentally more sympathetic to the goals of these two businesses than I am, but generally he provides an even-handed account that saves room for critique. I agree that these businesses are likely signals of a new economy, but I don’t know hat I am quite as enthusiastic about that possibility as Stone is. It will be interesting to see what happens when these business models become sufficiently common that they don’t require a connection to messianic founders to be viable.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/973280358">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0316388394/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 13:19:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/01/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>New Projects</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>Last night I started a new side project for the first time in over a year. I installed Django, I initialized a Git repository, and I created an app.</p>

<p>For the last several months, I have been putting pressure on myself to study and learn some new skills. I have made some progress, but also find myself going for long periods without working with these materials.</p>

<p>The feeling of having a project, for me, makes things different. I have a bucket to put this learning into and a scaffolding on which to try out some of these ideas. I have somewhere to go and do something when I find myself with a free 30 minutes.</p>

<p>I’m excited to feel this way again.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 16:44:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/26/new-projects.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/26/new-projects.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mapping Caps Lock to Escape in macOS Sierra</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I use Vim and command mode in any GUI editors that support it, so I’m hitting the Esc key hundreds of times a day. I’ve always been curious about mapping my Caps Lock key to escape to cut down on the distance I have to reach, but it used to require <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/127591/using-caps-lock-as-esc-in-mac-os-x#8437594">quite a bit of complexity</a>.</p>

<p>I recently moved to a new MacBook Pro with a Touch Bar and a virtual Esc key, so I decided to look into it again.</p>

<p>As of macOS Sierra 10.12.1, it’s incredibly simple.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Open System Preferences</li>
  <li>Go to the Keyboard pane and select the Keyboard tab</li>
  <li>Click the Modifier Keys… button on the bottom right</li>
  <li>From the popup menu to the right of “Caps Lock (⇪) Key”, select “⎋ Escape”</li>
</ol>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/12/caps-lock-to-escape.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/12/caps-lock-to-escape.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Disrupted and Blitzed</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0316306096/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Dan Lyons. <i>Disrupted: My Misadventure in the Start-Up Bubble</i>. New York: Hachette Books, 2016.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Dan Lyons’s memoir of his time as a conspicuously older employee in the twenty-something culture of HubSpot is a readable and entertaining evisceration of both the obvious and some of the more insidious poisonous aspects of Silicon Valley workplace culture. His experience as a tech journalist at <em>Newsweek</em> and elsewhere means that he also from time to time has some interesting insights into the strengths (and more often weaknesses) of HubSpot’s business which makes more edifying reading than a simple tour through a horror show.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/917344238">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0316306096/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1416507787/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Clifford Stoll. <i>The Cuckoo’s Egg: Tracking a Spy Through the Maze of Computer Espionage</i>. New York: Pocket Books, 2005.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I love post-mortem and process reading. <em>The Cuckoo’s Egg</em> is essentially a narrativization of Cliff Stoll’s logbook of a months-long surveillance of a hacker on his Berkeley computer lab’s Unix systems, and I found the sincere, guileless enthusiasm and detail with which he chronicled his work fascinating. From a historical perspective, the different level of infosec expectations at relatively sensitive sites on this early Internet compared versus basic consumer security expectations more than thirty years later is striking.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/804817769">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1416507787/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1937557383/ref=nosim/latin031-20">David Demaree. <i>Git for Humans</i>. New York: A Book Apart, 2016.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I use Git all day every day but, probably like most, only barely scratch the surface of its functionality. From a practical standpoint, Demaree’s book also does not go particularly deep into esoteric features of the software; I might have learned one or two practical tips and tricks. The book is instead a concise, accessible encapsulation of Git’s design perspective meant to help people engage with it on its own terms. As with many of the books in the <a href="https://abookapart.com/">A Book Apart</a> series, its strength comes in the tightness and directness of its purpose. It’s difficult to point to a single insight that I have not yet encountered elsewhere or stumbled upon on my own, but I nonetheless have a better sense of what to expect from Git from encountering all of these ideas together, organized in this way, and articulated this clearly and succinctly.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/946886836">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1937557383/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        
    <span class="citation">
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1328663795/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Norman Ohler. <i>Blitzed: Drugs in the Third Reich</i>. Translated by Shaun Whiteside. Boston: Houghton Mifflin Harcourt, 2017.</a>
      
    </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Having spent last year in Berlin (and returning this year for the summer), I’ve been getting back into reading twentieth century European for the first time in roughly twenty years. Having heard about <em>Blitzed</em> on the <a href="http://dobyfriday.com/19">Do By Friday</a> podcast, I thought it would introduce a lighter vein to that area of my reading. Ohler is not as historiographically disciplined as a writer trained as a historian might be, but his account is nonetheless at least very suggestive and is certainly entertaining and disturbing. Sometimes the account—particularly in its riffs on the relationship between Hitler and his private physician—may indulge a little too much in the salacious for my tastes, but Ohler’s central conceit that the story of Hitler’s dependency and perhaps addictions is essential for its subversion of Nazism’s claim to moral purity is convincing.</p>
</span>
        
        
    <span class="links">
      
        <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/965781501">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      
      
        <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1328663795/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      
    </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 22:30:01 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/disrupted-and-blitzed.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/disrupted-and-blitzed.html</guid>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>