<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>La Tinaja</title>
<description>My name is Brian Jones. These are my notes on topics including books, publishing, tech, and history.</description>
<link>http://tinaja.computer</link>
<atom:link href="http://tinaja.computer/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Oddments</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I’ve set up a new small web page I’m calling <a href="https://oddments.brianjon.es">Oddments</a> to collect links to and information about projects I’m working on.</p>

<p>I’m hoping that having a place to collect these things will provide some motivation to keep building them.</p>

<p>I keep bouncing back and forth on the value of having hobbies and pursuits that generate ephemeral products. On the one hand it is the case that the pressure to conceive of any freetime pursuit as something to be connected to a larger project or to be productized or otherwise commodified is a powerful trap. On the other, my life at the moment makes for such infrequent moments of freedom to play that having leisure pursuits that produce lasting products is a nice reminder that I do in fact have hobbies.</p>

<p>So here is <a href="https://oddments.brianjone.s">Oddments</a>. Let’s hope it keeps growing.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/01/26/oddments.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/01/26/oddments.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Listening, Endurance, and the Inland Empire</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B078W646XC/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Kate Atkinson, <i>Transcription</i>, New York: Little, Brown and Company, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p><em>Transcription</em> is an interesting sort of spy novel which operates in several different historical contexts. The protagonist works surveillance for a sting operation on Nazi sympathizers in wartime London. Her wartime experiences and relationships reappear as obligations in her post-war life working in children’s radio programming for the BBC. She returns to London late in life from a long life spent abroad. In each of these chronological frames there are connections and tensions implied, but things don’t come together until the end in a satisfying revelation.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1057615349">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B078W646XC/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B0716GZX33/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Alex Hutchinson, <i>Endure: Mind, Body, and the Curiously Elastic Limits of Human Performance</i>, New York: William Morrow, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I found this synthesis of the contemporary science on human endurance fascinating. The author is a runner and much of the subject matter has to do with running, but it is more than a book about running. The chapters are arranged thematically—collected around subjects such as diet, cardiovascular fitness, pain, and mental stamina—but a constant is the importance of person’s frame of mind and perception of their situation on their capacity for endurance. I found the material interesting in its own right, but I’m also curious about the potential to apply some of the insights about frame of mind to my own running.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1012647794">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B0716GZX33/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B07869VTBL/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jonathan Lethem, <i>The Feral Detective: A Novel</i>, New York: Ecco Books, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I grabbed <em>The Feral Detective</em> in a rush at the airport in Houston over Christmas, knowing nothing about it and spending way more money than I intended for a new release hardcover. I loved it. In its own peculiar way, it fits into the long legacy of the outsider L.A. detective. It is alternatingly funny and shocking and harrowing. Its relationship to the geography of the Mojave Desert and the foothills of the San Gabriel Mountains feels very real. It is the first work of fiction I personally have encountered composed of and for the moment of the Trump presidency, and in my opinion it earns its opportunity to represent this cultural moment. I strongly recommend it.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1066473445">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B07869VTBL/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 14:43:00 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/01/21/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/01/21/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mortadella Dürüm and Authenticity</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>From <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/08/dining/momofuku-bang-bar-review.html">Pete Wells’s review</a> of David Chang’s Bang Bar:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>I’ve saved the breakfast mini with mortadella for last, although it’s been the subject of the most rapt online attention. Building logs of mortadella layered with lardo and roasting them on spits is exactly the sort of thing the Momofuku group was put on this earth to do. I am glad this revolving meat torpedo exists. I respect Bang Bar’s cooks — this collaborative effort has no chef, Mr. Chang said in a phone interview — for realizing that the proper garnish for caramelized mortadella shavings is a slice of yellow American cheese and hot mustard. I appreciate the respect the sandwich pays to both fried baloney and Taylor Ham. And if I were in the habit of turning up at Columbus Circle with a hangover in the mornings, I would probably become a regular consumer of mortadella minis with Ssam Sauce. With a clear head and stomach, though, the saltiness can be a little too bracing.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>This fried-baloney-sandwich-as-mortadella-dürüm sounds amazing and is precisely the kind of thinking high-low, free-associating that makes me to ready to buy pretty much anything David Chang is selling. It’s also a poignant illustration of the possibilities opened by leaving the authenticity trap experienced by so many non-white restaurant owners in the U.S., as <a href="https://ny.eater.com/2019/1/18/18183973/authenticity-yelp-reviews-white-supremacy-trap">argued recently</a> by Sarah Kay.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/01/19/mortadella-durum.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/01/19/mortadella-durum.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Launching Local Memory</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>This morning I finally made the first public link to a project I’ve been working on for two years. It’s finished; Michael and I will continue adding new content and new features, but it is now complete enough to share publicly.</p>

<p><a href="https://local-memory.org">Local Memory: A History of Music in Austin</a> is a public history project we’re presenting as a website. Our first exhibit, <a href="https://local-memory.org/athens-on-the-colorado">Athens on the Colorado</a>, explores the dominance of the university campuses and communities in defining most audiences’ encounter with music performance in the 1930s and 1940s in Austin. This exhibit will continue to expand, and we have started working on our next exhibit as well.</p>

<p>The project also presents a database of performances, artists, and venues. So far, the bulk of the effort around this material has focused on making internal tools to digest and clean up the data. We still have a lot more data to process and pull into the site, but we have enough of a foundation (a little over 2000 performances) to start working with more interesting ways of exploring and presenting the data as well.</p>

<p>On the technical side, I’ve built the site using <a href="https://gatsbyjs.org">Gatsby</a>, the React-based static-site builder. It has been a good way to force myself to learn React (and get increasingly comfortable with the modern JavaScript syntax toolchain in general), and I anticipate writing up some of the things I’ve worked on in connection to that as well.</p>

<p>Mostly it feels good to finally be able to give a little oxygen to this project that has been under wraps for so long. It’s exciting to think that now work done on new features will have a much shorter path to entering the wild. (It’s also exciting to see the new time for other personal projects opening in the near future.)</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/01/10/launching-local-memory.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/01/10/launching-local-memory.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Pirates, Street Food, and Hurricanes</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1616958375/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Ed Lin. <i>Ghost Month</i>. New York: Soho Crime, 2014.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The bones of this book suggest a pretty straight-forward thriller set largely in a night market in Taipei. The suspense works, and the characters mostly have a couple of individual elements layered on their trope-y roles. The thing that sets it apart is greater-than-usual attention to detail in setting the scene around plot. I found the detail about the Taiwanese setting  interesting, and it was informative for me as someone who knows little about the place. I sometimes found myself wishing that the novel’s ambitions were set a bit higher to make more use of the texture available to it from this scene-setting work, but this was nonetheless an enjoyable and worthwhile leisure read.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1000300864">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1616958375/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01FKU5ECI/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Erik Larson. <i>Isaac’s Storm: A Man, a Time, and the Deadliest Hurricane in History</i>. New York: Vintage Books, 2000.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I’ve meant to read <em>Isaac’s Storm</em> forever. Galveston is one of my favorite places, and it had become a source of at least a little embarrassment that there existed this incredibly widely-read book by an incredibly successful non-fiction author that I had not read. When my friend recently recommended it again, I decided to read it. Since the book was first published, some of the meteorological history and climatology has become of more ‘professional’ interest to me as my dissertation wandered adjacent to climate science history. There is a strong sense of place evoked; the Galveston presented here is familiar. I am an atypical reader in having strong personal interests in both the Galveston history and the meteorological history, but in that context, the litany of anecdotes of individual tragedies during the storm wore on my patience more than anything else. I understand that others would not be likely to have the same reaction.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/475205969">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01FKU5ECI/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/150191947">Christophe Blain. <i>Parijs</i>. Isaac de piraat, vol. 4. Translated by Pieter van Oudheusden. Amsterdam: Oog & Blik, 2006.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I have started to practice my Dutch by checking strips out from the library in Gent. This is the first I’ve had a chance to finish. This volume is the fourth in the series, so it took me a while to get my bearings. I would like to return to the beginning if I can find the first volume. Isaac “the pirate” is a French painter who falls in with a group of pirates on his travels to the New World. This installment covers his return to Paris to find the world of artists he left dissolved and his father ill. One of his pirate friends has accompanied them, and they get caught up in the Parisian underworld. It is not the adventure story that the setting and synopsis might suggest; it is more of a character study. I’m curious to see if this represents an evolution of the series as it returns to France or if this was the dynamic from the beginning.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/150191947">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 05:50:00 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/12/21/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/12/21/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tuning Memory for a Self-Hosted Mastodon Instance</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I recently started hosting my own <a href="https://masto.brianjon.es/@brian">Mastodon instance</a>, but was having a difficult time getting it to run on the low-end Droplet configuration at DigitalOcean. I was happy to run this experiment at $5/mo, but $10/mo was too much for the long term.</p>

<p>I found <a href="https://github.com/tootsuite/documentation/blob/master/Running-Mastodon/Tuning.md#using-jemalloc">this section</a> in the Mastodon administration docs that recommends running <a href="http://jemalloc.net/">jemalloc</a> to reduce Mastodon’s memory footprint.</p>

<p>It was easy to do and has allowed me to run on the low-end Droplet from DigitalOcean without running out of memory. I still need to upgrade to the next size when I upgrade Mastodon, but then I can size back down for normal operation.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 08:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/12/04/memory-on-self-hosted-mastodon.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/12/04/memory-on-self-hosted-mastodon.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Spies and Cooking</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0393254151/ref=nosim/latin031-20">David Ignatius. <i>The Quantum Spy: A thriller</i>. New York: W.W. Norton & Company, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>In theory I like pulpy airport spy thrillers, but am almost always disappointed when I take a chance on one from an unfamiliar author. I don’t feel like I read enough to waste time on ones that aren’t great examples of the form. I listened to an interview with David Ignatius whom I know as a foreign policy journalist. When he revealed he’s also been a spy novelist for most of his career, I decided I should check it out. I will read more. All of the thriller mechanics were solid and engrossing, and the specifics of the world—quantum computing, tech espionage, Big Science bureaucracy—all felt non-stupid.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/985974585">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0393254151/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B004HYHB48/ref=nosim/latin031-20">David Downing. <i>Zoo Station</i>. New York: SoHo Crime, 2007.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The protagonist is a British journalist living and working in late 1930s Berlin. I bought the e-book on a promotion primarily out of interest in the setting. Unfortunately the construction of that setting frequently relies more on the name-dropping of streets and locations more than it does on evoking a feeling. However, the very British espionage thriller technique of having someone adjacent to events—a journalist, in this case—thrust into a cloak and dagger world and the mundane mechanics of negotiating the situation saved it for me. It is the first of a series, and I think I will read more. Even though I was a bit disappointed in the world-building, there were passages that suggest to me that future iterations may improve in that regard as well.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/899965461">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B004HYHB48/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1324002646/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Michael Lewis. <i>The Fifth Risk</i>. New York: W.W. Norton & Company, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is a short book exclusive to Amazon that I listened to as an audio book. Because he is such an efficient storyteller and concise stylist, I find that Michael Lewis’s books work particularly well as audiobooks. This one was an eye-opening analysis of the risks around the Trump administration’s failure to address basic administrative responsibilities across the bureaucracy. Lewis suggests (compellingly) that as abhorrent as the administration’s rhetoric is, the incompetence and lack of interest in basic governance has the potential to be more catastrophic.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1057554927">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1324002646/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/006210330X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Karen Le Billon. <i>French Kids Eat Everything: How Our Family Moved to France, Cured Picky Eating, Banished Snacking, and Discovered 10 Simple Rules for Raising Happy, Healthy Eaters</i>. New York: William Morrow, 2012.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Another iteration in the genre of ‘fish out of water’ parenting experiences, this one tracks the experiences of a Vancouver-born woman married to a Frenchmen when they moved their family of four to the small village in Brittany where he grew up. It adheres to genre tropes of possibly exagerrated mea culpas around the author’s personal history of feeding her family in comparison to the enlightened ease with which the French around her succeed at the same task. Nonetheless, Le Billon is an engaging writer, so the stories are fun, and her research into French social science on child development and nutrition was very interesting. I found myself wishing that we had a similar experience in our Belgian school as she did with her French school around the centrality of eating properly (as in eating as a behavior or a pursuit, rather than as a means of nutrition) in early education. It has inspired me to try some of her techniques in bringing unfamiliar Belgian dishes into our dinner routine at home; we have a year to see if it will work out.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/937840155">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/006210330X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B0052RDIGY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Kathleen Finn. <i>The Kitchen Counter Cooking School: How a Few Simple Lessons Transformed Nine Culinary Novices into Fearless Home Cooks</i>. New York: Penguin Books, 2014.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Kathleen Finn was already an accomplished food writer when she embarked on the entrepreneurial task of identifying and remedying many American homemakers’ fear of basic cooking skills and difficult relationships with food and feeding families that results. In its specifics, the book is a memoir of teaching a small cooking basics class to a group of volunteer students and, more generally,  an exploration of the practice of cooking as a form of self-care and a path to self-care and a lamentation of the decline of basic food knowledge as a result of postwar processed food marketing. There are recipes and techniques taken from the class which would be of interest to the reader who was a candidate for her class. I appreciated it mostly for the dicussions of the process of building the class and identifying the needs of her students.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/883321324">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B0052RDIGY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 15:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/11/24/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/11/24/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Shipwrecks, Lafayette, Vancouver</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00NDTV6W6/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Robert Kurson. <i>Pirate Hunters: Treasure, Obsession, and the Search for a Legendary Pirate Ship</i>. New York: Random House, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I listened to the bulk of this as an audiobook while running the Louisville Marathon. It’s perhaps not surprising that I wish there were more attention paid to the history, but what is there is actually pretty well done. The exploration of the specific techniques and practice of treasure diving was very interesting. I was less interested in the macho adventure-hero framing around the lives of the main subjects, but I get why it was there.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/966049184">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00NDTV6W6/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/941381351">Rachel Andrew. <i>Get Ready for CSS Grid Layout</i>. Briefs, 1. New York: A Book Apart, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is the first of <a href="https://abookapart.com/">A Book Apart’s</a> Briefs collection of e-book-only publications on short-form topics. I bought this when it came out and never got around to reading it. Now that CSS Grid is more of a reality instead of a developing spec, some of it is a bit outdated, but it is still a very concise and useful introduction to the goals and organizing principles of CSS grid. It makes for a great foundation from which to ramp up quickly through personal experimentation or reading examples online.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/941381351">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307742822/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Guanzhong Chen. <i>The Fat Years</i>. Translated by Michael S. Duke. New York: Anchor Books, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is an interesting satirical speculative fiction story set in very near future China from the perspective of 2011 with some plot elements that give it a little bit of a light science fiction feel. The cultural specificities of the setting necessary to understand the satire would largely have been lost on me without some explanatory notes from the translator responsible for the English language edition. That separation meant it was not always a smooth read, but I am nonetheless glad to have read it.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/976014241">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307742822/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0743243803/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Sarah Vowell. <i>The Partly Cloudy Patriot</i>. New York: Simon & Schuster, 2002.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The audiobook productions of Sarah Vowell’s books are all really great. Reading her own words in her very individual voice presents the dry humor in precisely the right tone, and the readers she gets to present the quotations from primary sources all do great readings. As usual Vowell is particularly interested in popular contemporary understanding of history and perceptions of her subjects. This time she takes the Marquis de Lafayette as her central character to elucidate some of the global connections and the contingencies of the American war of independence that are perhaps not part of most contemporary Americans’ basic understanding of their history.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/49649932">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0743243803/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1596911050/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Douglas Coupland. <i>JPod</i>. Toronto: Random House of Canada, 2006.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Our friends left this on the shelf of their house where we’re living in Gent this year. I hadn’t read it since it came out, but I’m a sucker for Coupland so I picked it up. I remember enjoying it on my first read, but thinking it was less substantial than his other work or not sufficiently additive as a clear successor to <em>Microserfs</em>. Reading it with another decade or so of hindsight, I actually have a great appreciation for it. I come away with the feeling that its slightness is precisely the point—that the characters’ quippiness as apparent substitutions for character traits rather than expressions of them is a consequence of informational ubiquity. Coupland was responding to a post-Google world, but the cultural and spiritual trajectory he identifies seem only more salient in our world that is both post-Google and post-Facebook.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/745958199">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1596911050/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 09:09:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/10/07/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/10/07/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>10 Podcasts You Might Not Listen To</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <ul>
  <li><a href="http://afropop.org/">Afropop Worldwide</a>: A long-tenured public radio show on music from Africa and across the African diaspora</li>
  <li><a href="http://cointalk.show">Coin Talk</a>: An irreverent weekly chat between Aaron Lammer and Jay Kang (and sometimes guests) on goings on in the cryptocurrency world</li>
  <li><a href="http://dankrares.com/">Dank Rares</a>: Interviews with people exploring the possibilities of blockchain technology for market-making in digital art</li>
  <li><a href="http://foodsafetytalk.com/">Food Safety Talk</a>: Commentary on recent news in food safety policy and research combined with shaggy, rambling chat about an array of other subjects between two food safety academics</li>
  <li><a href="https://soundcloud.com/gamething">GAMETHING</a>: Small collages of sound, voiceover, and music created in response to video game experiences</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.southernfoodways.org/gravy-format/gravy-podcast/">Gravy</a>: Tightly produced programs on food and culture topics in the U.S. South from the Southern Foodways Alliance</li>
  <li><a href="https://the.hobbyhorse.club/">Hobby Horse</a>: Matt Haughey interviews people about a personal interest or hobby outside of their field of expertise</li>
  <li><a href="https://toomuchnotenough.site">Too Much Not Enough</a>: Chats between Emma Winston and Darius Kazemi in which they take turns introducing each other to topics of obsessive interest</li>
  <li><a href="https://postlight.com/tag/podcast">Track Changes</a>: Chats between Postlight agency founders Paul Ford and Rich Ziade (and frequently guests) on topics in business and technology</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.20k.org/">Twenty Thousand Hertz</a>: Like a 99% Invisible for sound design</li>
</ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/10/04/podcasts.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/10/04/podcasts.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Murder, Coffee, and Austin</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250056454/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Judith Flanders. <i>A Murder of Magpies</i>. New York: Minotaur Books, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This was a quick, light, and well-written cozy mystery set in the world of London publishing. Scott McNulty recommended it on the <a href="https://www.theincomparable.com/recentlyread/19/">Recently Read</a> podcast, and my feelings about it essentially reflect his. This is very well-executed fun that is absolutely satisfying.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/908085186">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250056454/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307390462/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Maj Sjöwall and Per Wahlöö. <i>Roseanna</i>. Translated by Lois Roth. New York: Vintage Books, 1976 [1967].</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I’ve had these Martin Beck detective stories recommended to me a lot, but finally got around to them having been triggered on Scandinavian detective fiction by something Warren Ellis wrote about Henning Mankell on his mailing list. As it turns out, Mankell contributed a foreword to the edition of <em>Roseanna</em> that I read. He praised similar aspects of Sjöwall’s writing as Ellis had in his, and perhaps not surprisingly these were the traits that I found most enjoyable in this book. There are a patience and a directness in the writing that make the world and characters feel very real. The tension of the police procedural elements are effective precisely by being couched in this realness; there is very little need for the sensational to heighten the stakes. I look forward to reading the rest.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/857990879">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307390462/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/034580709X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jo Nesbø. <i>The Bat</i>. Translated by Don Bartlett. New York: Vintage, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>It turns out this is the second time I’ve read this. I had the sensation off and on in the beginning that I had, but given that the events of this story serve as flashback material for later novels in the series I wasn’t sure. By the time I was certain, I was hooked again and blazed through the whole thing again. One thing I noticed this time was the use of Australian vocabulary and dialect in the English translation in a way that makes me wonder what was done in the Norwegian original.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/855252507">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/034580709X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1101947314/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Dave Eggers. <i>The Monk of Mokha</i>. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I generally prefer Eggers’s narrative nonfiction to his novels. The shifts of frame between analysis and characterization, the global and the individual in the medium allow his powerfully concise expression to shine. He also has a strong instinct for taking real individuals and turning them into emblems of a larger moment. In this case, his protagonist Mokhtar’s story is so very 2018 in its elucidation of the growing inequities of urban America (and the Bay Area specifically), the Sillicon-Valley-ization of American business culture, the immigrant experience in America, the fallout in the rest of the world of the American War on Terror, the evolution of consumer tastes, and so many other. There is so much going on here and yet it reads easy.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1040273087">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1101947314/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/163149287X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">J.R. Helton. <i>Bad Jobs and Poor Decisions: Dispatches from the Working Class: A Memoir</i>. New York: Liveright Publishing Corporation, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I bought this based off of a mention by Will Menaker on the Chapo Trap House podcast last year. His recommendation and most of the reviews focus on the insight into the experience of the American working class in the 1980s. It is an interesting portrait of someone moving from under-paying, over-taxing job to job and bouncing between periods of precarity and relative stability, and Helton is both an empathetic and a direct writer. My primary personal interest, however, was in the setting. Helton’s twenties were spent in the Austin I saw as a kid that made me want to move there. It was an Austin that still existed for the most part as I arrived in the late nineties and disappeared over the course of the seventeen years I lived there. I think a lot of these experiences are still there to be had, but they are definitely by no means still one of the basic default lifestyle choices for Austin twenty-somethings. Though most of my experience did not match some of the extremes in here, it was in its outlines absolutely congruent. I don’t miss quite a bit of that, but it was a nice opportunity for reflection.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/988282578">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/163149287X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1481497499/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Catherynne M. Valente. <i>Space Opera</i>. New York: Saga Press, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I saw this recommended in a lot of different venues. I think a lot of the enthusiasm for it in the specific venues I saw it has to do with the fluid sexual preferences and gender roles that undergird a lot of the tensions between characters. That was nice to see, but I didn’t really find much revelatory in it. It was just sort of there, which is good in its own way. There’s something to be said for something reaching the point for its presence in a piece of genre fiction to be rather banal. There’s a lot of over-the-top energy and playfulness in the language. Sometimes I found that fun; sometimes I found it a little exhausting. It’s a big long book full of tons of ideas that I enjoyed but was also a little glad to be released from.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/989963881">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1481497499/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0385508603/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Ellen Ullman. <i>The Bug: A Novel</i>. New York: Anchor Books, 2004.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I’ve been meaning to read this for a very long time and having finally gotten around to it regret that it has taken so long. Ullman is such a great, empathetic writer that reading this also highlighted for me how rew novels in which computing plays a major role in plot and setting actually use the computing as a thematic tool. In some ways, this could have been a story about isolation, obsession, and frustrated human communication among people in any occupation; on the other, the peculiar nature of the work of programming and the obsessive tendencies of its practitioners are essential to the protagonist’s individual path to self-destruction. It strikes me that this tension between the universal and the specific would be a defining characteristic of an artful and humane novel.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/56079814">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0385508603/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0785196587/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Tom King, Gabriel Hernandez, Jordie Bellaire, and Clayton Cowles. <i>The Vision, Vol. 2: Little Better than a Beast</i>. New York: Marvel, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I enjoyed the first volume of this quite a bit, but realized in reading the second volume that most of what I got out of it was the world-building and characterization. Once those things had been set, I was less interested in the progression of the narrative and character arcs. There was a little bit too much of a heightened melodrama feel. I recognize that it was interesting and ambitious in the context of mainstream superhero comics, but I think I maybe prefer my unconventional-risk-reads in this format to be subversively fun rather than subversively serious.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1035694563">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0785196587/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 09:09:40 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/27/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/27/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>