<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>La Tinaja</title>
<description>My name is Brian Jones. These are my notes on topics including books, publishing, tech, and history.</description>
<link>http://tinaja.computer</link>
<atom:link href="http://tinaja.computer/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Girl Detectives, Soccer, and VHS Tapes</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0465094481/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Laurent Dubois. <i>The Language of the Game: How to Understand Soccer</i>. New York: Basic Books, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I read this while the World Cup was on. I know Laurent Dubois from my graduate work reading the Atlantic World historiography, but since then he has become one of my favorite writers on sports as well. This book is arranged in chapters using different participants in the game—players by position, managers, referees, fans—to anchor thematic observations on politics, gender, race, and culture in soccer.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1029830233">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0465094481/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062430483/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jason Fagone. <i>The Woman Who Smashed Codes: A True Story of Love, Spies, and the Unlikely Heroine Who Outwitted America’s Enemies</i>. New York: Dey Street Books, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I was completely unaware of the specifics of the bureaucratic apparatus (and really lack thereof) for code breaking during World War II, but that is hardly the only interesting aspect of this. Not only are there many other axes of interest for history of science and technology in the different communities of research and scholarship that Elizebeth Friedman moved through, but I appreciate Fagone’s enthusiastic championing of his subject and her largely unheralded work.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1005678196">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062430483/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0785196579/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Tom King, Gabriel Hernandez, Jordie Bellaire, and Clayton Cowles. <i>The Vision, Vol. 1: Little Worse than a Man</i>. New York: Marvel, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Max Temkin strongly recommended this on the <a href="http://dobyfriday.com">Do By Friday</a> podcast. I think there may be a little bit of context I’m missing from not being familiar with the larger story of Vision, but nonetheless I thought it was a pretty interesting exploration of what makes community (through both exclusion and inclusion) and how identities are constructed.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/995294999">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0785196579/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250159997/ref=nosim/latin031-20">John Darnielle. <i>Universal Harvester: A Novel</i>. New York: Picador, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p><em>Universal Harvester</em> builds a strong sense of place in late 90s Iowa in which its quiet, suspenseful almost-horror sits neatly next to people living with loss and grief. Darnielle’s experience building characters in the small spaces of songs shows itself in his knack for finding the small exemplary. This writing felt patient and confident; I really enjoyed being in and moving slowly through this world.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/981966720">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250159997/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1400067219/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Kurt Andersen. <i>Fantasyland: How America Went Haywire</i>. New York: Random House, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Kurt Andersen traces the development of magical thinking and individualistic ‘truth’ in American culture from early English settlement to the present day. He does a good job summarizing the early modern cultural history. It’s a survey, and I’m not the imagined audience for it, but it was nice to see this perspective on early American Protestant religion in a work of popular nonfiction. Andersen’s clear interest is in the second half of the twentieth century when he argues that the American predeliction for personal truth, facilitated by the counterculture and postmodernism, allow for an explosion of non-reality-based worldviews across the political and cultural spectrum. The obvious endpoint is the era of the Trump presidency. In tying this moment to a long history fusing individualistic and supernatural worldviews into a uniquely American epistemology, Andersen helpfully challenges the idea that this Trumpist moment is some kind of catastrophic rupture rather than inherently American.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1027554418">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1400067219/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01L2WGIQY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Hope Larson and Brittney Williams. <i>Goldie Vance, vol. 1</i>. Los Angeles: BOOM! Box, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I picked this out at the comic book store with Mees having seen it mentioned before as a good book for kids. It’s a nice Nancy Drew- or Harriet the Spy-like girl-detective story about a precocious teenager who takes it upon herself to act as house detective at South Florida hotel where her father works in a early 1960s setting. The primary young characters are people of color and the teen romance is not exclusively heterosexual. The artwork is colorful and fun, and the action is mostly non-violent. It was a worthwhile read for my own enjoyment, but it’s also definitely a great option for non-superhero comics for kids.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1045029093">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01L2WGIQY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0345807154/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jo Nesboø. <i>Cockroaches: The Second Inspector Harry Hole Novel</i>. London: Harvill Secker, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>When I started reading the Harry Hole series, the installment available in English was <em>The Redbreast</em>, which is actually the third book in the series. Almost ten years later, it’s interesting to return to this earlier entry. It’s a page-turner the way they all are. Having spent a short time in Bangkok staying with Northern European ex-pat friends, it was interesting to see Nesbø’s frame for conflicts between Thai and ex-pat culture, particularly as he seems to experience it differently as a Northern European than I do as an American.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/875496861">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0345807154/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062409166/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Neal Stephenson and Nicole Galland. <i>The Rise and Fall of D.O.D.O.: A Novel</i>. New York: William Morrow, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This was lighter reading than some Stephenson fare—more like <em>Zodiac</em> than <em>Sevenes</em>—and ends up as a sort of time-traveling heist novel that mashes up Big Science and the occult, the military and academia. The narrative is presented in letters, networked groupware messaging platforms, and journals. On both these counts it’s reminiscent of other things I’ve read recently, but far more successful. I’m not familiar with Nicole Galland, but I’m sort of curious to read her historical fiction now, and I’m glad to see indications that this is the first installment in a series.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/959038737">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062409166/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 10:35:40 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/04/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/04/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Shadow Government, Stretching, and the Russo-Turkish War</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B075JN7XR1/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Adam Rothstein. <i>Orthogonal Procedures: A Novel</i>. New York: Arche Press, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I’ve read a lot of Adam Rothstein’s non-fiction work. This is is his first novel. It’s an alternate history thriller of a (more) technocratic twentieth century United States. The thematic trappings of the setting—bureaucracy, the occult, infrastructure, futurism—are right up my alley, but sometimes the descriptive flavoring derailed the forward momentum of the plot for me. I’d like to see more if these first novel kinks were to get sorted out.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1018490070">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B075JN7XR1/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1635651786/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Eiko. <i>Even the Stiffest People Can Do the Splits: A 4-Week Stretching Plan to Achieve Amazing Health</i>. New York: Rodale, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I came across this book through <a href="https://kottke.org/18/02/even-the-stiffest-people-can-do-the-splits">Jason Kottke</a> and thought it seemed interesting. I’ve been having a lot of hip flexor problems with my marathon training, so I was interested in the content itself, but I was also interested in the publishing phenomenon. I haven’t actually started the stretching program (although I still plan to), but the book as a published object definitely didn’t disappoint. The first third or so outlines the mechanics of the stretching program and actually does so in a really thoughtful and clearly presented way, but the final two thirds were the memorable part. The book ends with a fictional parable the length of a short novella about aging, keeping up appearances at the workplace, and other middle aged and middle class concerns meant to frame the shameful consequences of not being mindful about health and wellness. It is exceedingly difficult to imagine an American fitness book including the same content.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1033485062">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1635651786/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0316267724/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Joe Ide. <i>IQ: A Novel</i>. New York: Mulholland Books, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is a relatively recent debut novel, but Ide’s second novel featuring this detective had already just come out in hardcover when I finally got around to reading it. Every library I’ve been in recently has been featuring the new book heavily in its recent fiction section, and I understand why. This is light fare, but very well-executed light fare: very readable, pretty decent verisimilitude in its L.A. setting, and a relatively unusual origin story for the detective protagonist. I expect I’ll continue reading the series as it develops.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/954570422">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0316267724/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B000FCK0YY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Boris Akunin. <i>The Turkish Gambit: A Novel</i>. Translated by Andrew Bromfield. New York: Random House, 2005.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is the second novel in a series of historical detective novels set in the late nineteenth century. I haven’t read the first, but intend to go back to do so now. The bulk of the action is set in Bulgaria during the Russo-Turkish War, and the plot follows the hunt to identify a Turkish agent within the Russian camps. In the context of this kind of historical espionage fare, there is some formal ambition to presentation. The protagonist is not actually the detective who is central to the series, but a young progressive woman who has followed her fiancé in an modern, egalitarian betrothal from St. Petersburg to the frontlines where he has volunteered to be a cryptographer. The reader follows the efforts of the detective character, Erast Fandorin, through her eventual engagement as his assistant. Each chapter begins with fictional excerpted news reports and essays from newspapers around Europe. This device provides some continental context for events of the plot, but also insight into the characters as many of the clippings are written by journalist characters embedded in the Russian camp. This is genre fiction, but very high quality genre fiction. I intend to read the rest of them.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1029320396">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B000FCK0YY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250160170/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Sara Zaske. <i>Achtung Baby: An American Mom on the German Art of Raising Self-Reliant Children</i>. New York: Picador, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I ordered this immediately when I saw it reviewed by <a href="https://slate.com/human-interest/2018/02/achtung-baby-by-sara-zaske-reviewed.html">Rebecca Shuman</a>, confident that the author’s experience as an American raising a young child in Berlin would make it a pleasant nostaliga read if nothing else. It was definitely that. Anecdotes about navigating the city’s child welfare bureaucracy in German or being admonished by random old ladies for not dressing a child warmly enough hit close to home. Descriptions of particularly spectacular playgrounds were immediately familiar. The book is not simply a memoir, however, but a critique of overanxious and overbearing American parenting in the context of the post-authoritarian late twentieth- and early twenty-first-century transformation in German childcare. The critique is interesting and helps to articulate some of the general sense of difference I witness between our approach and that of other parents in the States. Some of that difference must simply come down to personality, but I think there is also an element of our having first learned to be parents in this German context. At this non-personal level, I think the book would be interested to anyone interested in reading about child development; it’s a good blend of light personal anecdote and synthesis of expert opinion and research.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1017757219">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250160170/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1524798053/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Rob Reid. <i>After On: A Novel of Silicon Valley</i>. New York: Del Rey, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This was a perfectly readable light satire of contemporary Silicon Valley culture. There is a primary narrative thread in an omniscient narrator’s voice supplemented by a variety of other kinds of texts and narrative perspectives. The primary thread is generally engaging and some of the formal experiments are entertaining and effective, but not all of them are and collectively they make me feel like this long book does not really earn its length. The story about the acquisition a struggling social network company by a rising Silicon Valley behemoth and the gradual revelation to them of a super AI could have been a tight, fun pageturner in slightly less ambitious packaging.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1014101741">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1524798053/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 17:11:01 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/05/20/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/05/20/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Sci-art, Shipping, and Germany</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00FPT5KJW/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Arthur I. Miller. <i>Colliding Worlds: How Cutting-Edge Science is Redefining Contemporary Art</i>. New York: W.W. Norton, 2014.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I really enjoyed this. It’s organized around three parts: a short history of shared interests between scientists and the artistic avant-garde, particularly in the early twentieth century; a catalog of recent and contemporary artists organized according to the scientific disciplines from which thy take material, techniques, and inspiration; and a short theoretical discussion of what these connections may mean for the practice of both art and science in the near future.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/995573570">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00FPT5KJW/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B009LRWJKW/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Rose George. <i>Ninety Percent of Everything: Inside Shipping, the Invisible Industry That Puts Clothes on Your Back, Gas in Your Car and Food on Your Plate</i>. New York: Picador, 2014.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>George uses a trip she takes as a supernumerary on a container ship from the UK to Southeast Asia via the Suez Canal as occasion to explore various angles of the maritime shipping industry: labor, corruption, environmental and economic consequences, etc. It’s all interesting, and the travelogue elements of her own experience on the ship and the lives of the sailors she gets to know are particularly engaging.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/942501172">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B009LRWJKW/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B071DLM6L4/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Robert Harris. <i>Munich</i>. New York: Knopf, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This was an enjoyable espionage thriller told from the perspectives of two old Oxford friends who end up on either side of the Munich Conference. I’ve read another one of Harris’s novels and appreciate his sensitivity to historical detail. It’s reminiscent of Le Carré novels where the spycraft and suspense all feel very human-scale.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1014283429">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B071DLM6L4/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1606909010/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Warren Ellis and Jason Masters. <i>Ian Fleming’s James Bond 007 Vol. 1: VARGR</i>. Mt. Laurel, N.J.: Dynamite Entertainment, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Not surprisingly coming from Ellis, this is a rather sardonic and brutal Bond story even though The Bond character himself is pretty light. It’s a good balance that triangulated a few of the movie Bond types and still feels true to the novels. The recognizable Berlin landscape details in the artwork were fun.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/942710328">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1606909010/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 16:48:01 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/04/13/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/04/13/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Aaron Koblin on art as experimentation</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>I do see art as experimentation. It’s fundamentally he process of combining things that have never been combined before. I’m fascinated by the process of translating ideas from one reality into another and ways that systems and structures can influence and guide new creation. To some extent art is an excuse. It’s a word that we use for yet-to-be-defined progress—necessary experiments in thought space which help us define and test limits. These are experiments that allow us to question, reflect, discover, and appreciate.</p>

  <p>– <cite><a href="http://www.aaronkoblin.com/">Aaron Koblin</a> on art as experimentation, as quoted in Arthur Miller’s <a href="http://amzn.to/2FCxfHk"><em>Colliding Worlds</em></a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 15:54:01 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/03/15/koblin.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/03/15/koblin.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Editor-Only CSS for the Elementor Page Builder</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>We’ve been experimenting recently with developing some in-house templates and tools to use on client projects based around WordPress and the <a href="http://elementor.com">Elementor</a> page builder plugin.</p>

<p>One problem that I’ve run into has been to retain the easy copy-editing benefits of using the WP administration panel and Elementor with more advanced interactive elements that might have hidden states on the initial page load. In these cases, the Elementor editor, which uses your theme’s stylesheet to give you WYSIWYG editing, will also hide those elements in the editing view.</p>

<p>I haven’t found this mentioned in the Elementor documentation, but it turns out that it inserts a class <code class="highlighter-rouge">elementor-editor-active</code> on the <code class="highlighter-rouge">&lt;body&gt;</code> tag while in the editor. You can add styles to your stylesheet to show or highlight special layout elements in ways they wouldn’t be displayed on the public site in order to help retain the ability to edit text using the visual editor.</p>

<p>Of course, you’re losing some of the WYSIWYG fidelity of using precisely the same styles as the public site, but some thoughtful presentation choices can minimize that downside.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 20:55:01 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/03/08/elementor-editor-styles.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/03/08/elementor-editor-styles.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Videogames, Fat, and Galveston</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01NAKSWW1/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jason Schreier. <i>Blood, Sweat, and Pixels: The Triumphant, Turbulent Stories of How Video Games are Made</i>. New York: Harper Paperbacks, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The organizational conceit of this book is to dedicate each chapter to short history of the development of a different videogame, and Schreier does a deft job of teasing a different thematic thread from each one. The unifying frame is the hardships the tension between rigid market schedules and the unpredictability of the medium can put on development teams, but each experience sounds terrible in its own way. Stardew Valley has basically been the entirety of my videogame universe for the past two years, so I was happy to see that represented, but I also found the coverage the AAA blockbuster projects much more interesting than I expected.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1005468687">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01NAKSWW1/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1524762237/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Mark Sisson. <i>The Keto Reset Diet: The Ketogenic Plan to Reboot Your Metablism in 21 Days and Burn Fat Forever</i>. New York: Harmony Books, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Ketogenic diets have been popular among tech people I’m aware of on the Internet for a while now, and I’ve been curious but have a difficult time not bouncing off of the voice of most diet books (and really self-help/self-improvement books generally). This author has his own line of “primal” (which as far as I can tell is branded paleo) food products and references them from time to time, but even with that the signal to sales noise ratio here is better than the average book of this sort. Skimming and following his citations to researchers was beneficial and having a prescribed meal plan to help get started with a new dietary regime is useful. This was a useful way to get into understanding what people are trying to accomplish in eating this way while requiring only a minimum amount of nose-holding against the self-promotional parts and references to some of the silly fellow traveler dietary stuff (e.g., “leaky gut syndrome”) that comes along with this topic that seems to have a kernel of non-bullshit at its core.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1004679044">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1524762237/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1439166668/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Nic Pizzolatto. <i>Galveston</i>. New York: Simon and Schuster, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I remember seeing this at Books on the Square when I was on a fellowship in Providence, RI when it first came out in 2010, and it’s taken me this long to get around to reading it. In the meantime, Pizzolatto has become famous for <em>True Detective</em>, so I may have gotten around to this regardless, but the book originally drew my attention as an aficionado of Galveston the place rather than interest in Pizzlatto as a writer. Having read it, Pizzolatto the writer is enjoyable. This is a good neo-noir novel with a strong sense of setting and an interesting protagonist. I wish I hadn’t initially been drawn by my love of Galveston the place, though. If it were simply a generic Gulf South setting, everything would be spot on, but whenever Pizzolatto is specific in a way that is supposed to lend verisimilitude, he gets just specific enough to land wrong, for example, describing turning from one street to another into a sunset that wouldn’t be in that direction or taking a highway past an area that would not in fact be visible from the road there. I was not searching for these details, and they don’t really matter, but it was a new experience for me to know a place so well and to have the fictional traversal of the space constantly rubbing up against my mental map of it. I imagine this feeling is a commonplace for people who know LA or New York better than I do.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1005486647">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1439166668/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 16:48:01 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/03/07/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/03/07/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Chris Coyier on Complexity in Web Development</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>I suspect it doesn’t need any more complexity, and literally nobody is advocating it does. That’s why that <em>the web is a big place</em> sentiment is so useful. We talk about complexity, but it’s all opt-in. A wonderfully useful (and simple) website of a decade ago remains wonderfully useful and simple. Fortunately for all involved, the web, thus far, has taken compatibility quite seriously. Old websites don’t just break.</p>

  <p>– <cite>Chris Coyier on <a href="https://css-tricks.com/complexity/">complexity in web development</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 15:50:01 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/02/26/complexity.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/02/26/complexity.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Leondardo da Vinci, kitchen manager</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>Master Leonardo da Vinci’s kitchen is a bedlam. Lord Ludovico Sforza told me that the effort of the last months had been to economize upon human labor, but now, instead of the twenty cooks the kitchens once employed, there are closer to two hundred persons milling in the area, and none that I could see cooking but all attending to the great devices that crowded up the floors and walls – and none of which seemed behaving in any manner useful or for which it was created. At one end a great waterwheel, driven by a raging waterfall, spewed and spattered forth its waters over all who passed beneath and made the floor a lake. Giant bellows, each twelve feet long, were suspended from the ceilings, hissing and roaring with intent to clear the fire smoke, but all they accoplished was to fan the flames. … And through this stricken area wandered horses and oxen … dragging Master Leondard’s floor-cleaning devices – performing their tasks valiantly, but also followed by another great army of men to clean the horses’ messes.</p>

  <p>– <cite>From a 1482 report describing the Sforza castle kitchen as managed by a 30-year-old Leonard da Vinci, as printed on the insert in the recent food-themed <a href="https://publicdomainreview.org/support/">postcard pack from <em>Public Domain Review</em></a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I had the chance to to help fulfill shipments on this most recent round of supporter packs. Consider becoming a <a href="https://publicdomainreview.org/support/">Friend of The Public Domain Review</a> to support the publication and get the next set.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 03:50:01 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/02/23/da-vinci-kitchen-manager.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/02/23/da-vinci-kitchen-manager.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>HTTPS on Github Pages Custom Domains with Cloudflare</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I’m hosting our archive site for <a href="https://theappendix.net"><em>The Appendix</em></a> on Github Pages because it’s free and it helps shield me from having to pay for the periodic bandwidth spike when an article or blog post gets popular for a few days on Reddit.</p>

<p>It has increasingly been bothering me that a  big problem with this solution long-term was the growing movement towards privileging web content served over HTTPS by services like Google as it conflicts with Github Pages inability to serve sites with custom domains over HTTPS. I was listening to the <a href="https://syntax.fm/show/033/large-files-cdns-image-compression-video-hosting-and-big-zips">Syntax podcast</a> yesterday when Wes made an aside that even free-tire <a href="http://cloudflare.com">Cloudflare</a> get served over HTTPS for free. That seemed like a solution to my problem.</p>

<p>I signed up for Cloudflare this morning, added the <code class="highlighter-rouge">theappendix.net</code> domain, changed my DNS settings to point to Cloudflare, and checked about 15 minutes later to find the site being served over HTTPS. Done.</p>

<p>This site is supposed to be an archive that will hopefully persist with little maintenance for a long, long time. In putting Cloudflare in front of it, I’ve added another layer of dependency. However, Cloudflare sits in front of the hosting. All I have to do to remove my dependency on it if it should disappear is to change my DNS settings again. As long as I’m maintaining the <code class="highlighter-rouge">theappendix.net</code> domain name I’ll be able to support at least that level of maintenance supervision.</p>

<p>One caveat is that Cloudflare’s free certificate is a shared SSL certificate which presents some security concerns. In the context of the problem I am trying to solve—providing a Github Pages-hosted static site over HTTPS—I don’t think those concerns are relevant; however, it will not be the correct approach to security for all situations.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 16:28:01 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/02/22/cloudflare-github-pages-https.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/02/22/cloudflare-github-pages-https.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Snakeheads, Weimar, and Marathons</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307279278/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Patrick Radden Keefe. <i>The Snakehead: An Epic Tale of the Chinatown Underworld and the American Dream</i>. New York: Doubleday, 2009.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I’ve had this on the shelf since very soon after it came out. It has followed me through several moves and for some reason never made it off the to read pile. I’m glad I finally did read it, and it was actually interesting to now read it with a bit of time having passed and in the context of our Trumpist/nativist era. Keefe centers his narrative around the rise of a Fujianese “snakehead” (or human smuggler) based in New York’s Chinatown known as Sister Peng to explore the global and local dynamics of human smuggling, particularly between Fuzhou and the United States in the 1990s. It was both informative as a piece of political journalism and entertaining on the level of true crime narrative.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/695693714">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307279278/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0393322394/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Peter Gay. <i>Weimar Culture: The Outsider as Insider</i>. New York: W.W. Norton, 2001 [1968].</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>It was interesting to read this in our current moment of rising worry over authoritarianism and to consider its having been written in 1968 as a reflection on one major twentieth-century moment of political upheaval from the midst of another. The most compelling part of the work is the interdisciplinary of the sources and cultural productions Gay surveys: theater, dance, music, film, literature, poetry, painting, etc.  Throughout these fields of creative endeavor—though to varying degrees—he argues that intellectual and creative elites were frequently not sufficiently committed to the revolutionary aims of the Republic and that this lack of cultural commitment was a strong contributor to its failure.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/670901653">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0393322394/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1451685858/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Ed Caesar. <i>Two Hours: The Quest to Run the Impossible Marathon</i>. New York: Simon and Schuster, 2015.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Caesar blends a history of professional marathoning and marathon training with a synthesis of contemporary research in fitness and physiology in this exploration of elite marathoners’ assault on the two hour mark. The narrative is centered on the Kenyan Geoffrey Mutai and weaves together thematic chapters on topics including the development of Kenyan distance running, doping, the tension between amateurism and professionalism in the history of the sport, and the rise of the city marathon circuit. I listened to this as an audiobook which doesn’t always lend itself well to keeping a meta-narrative in one’s head, but Caesar does an exceptional job of balancing individual anecdotes with returns to the connective tissue of his argument(s).</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/966496292">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1451685858/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 21:03:01 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/02/16/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/02/16/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>