<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>La Tinaja</title>
<description>My name is Brian Jones. These are my notes on topics including books, publishing, tech, and history.</description>
<link>http://tinaja.computer</link>
<atom:link href="http://tinaja.computer/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: October 19, 2017</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B074TJ8M94/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Eva Holland. <i>Mussolini’s Arctic Airship</i>. Seattle, WA: Amazon Kindle Singles, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Holland centers the story of the wreck of the airship <em>Italia</em> over the Arctic on the Norwegian explorer Roald Amundsen and the path that put him on the rescue mission that ended his life. Produced as a Kindle Single, the work is compact, but alternates capably between the long historical trajectory of Amundsen’s career, the European geopolitics of the interwar period, and experience of the wrecked crew of the <em>Italia</em>. In particular, the narrative of the wreck provides a good example of creating narrative tension in moments of peril from relatively limited and contradictory primary sources.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B074TJ8M94/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1302900536/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Ta-Nehisi Coates and Brian Stelfreeze. <i>Black Panther: A Nation Under Our Feet, vol. 1</i>. New York: Marvel, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This opening volume of Ta-Nehisi Coates’s take on Black Panther was both impressive and a bit difficult to get into. It took me until the final issue of this collection to feel like I was on firm footing with the several storylines (and their different scales) going on. The story is very much embedded in our current historical moment of re-examination of our history of racial conflict, populist discontent, and armed conflict with non-state actors while also being engaged with comic book history in its skepticism with regard to the singular hero. From a packaging standpoint, including early appearances of Black Panther is a nice touch, and I hope that continues in future collections.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/968293730">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1302900536/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1302900544/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Ta-Nehisi Coates and Chris Sprouse. <i>Black Panther: A Nation Under Our Feet, vol. 2.</i> New York: Marvel, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I read this second volume straight on from the first, and much of my reaction to this second installment is the same. The main change is the inclusion of ‘The Crew’ comprised of Storm, Luke Cage, Manifold, and Misty Knight which provides some opportunity for some lighter dialogue to break up the heavy monologuing of the first volume of stories.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/951950785">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1302900544/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0143127438/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Paul Greenberg. <i>American Catch: The Fight for Our Local Seafood</i>. New York: The Penguin Press, 2014.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Paul Greenberg takes three sea creatures—the Eastern Oyster, the Gulf Shrimp, and the Alaskan Salmon—that typify North Americans’ historical engagement with seafood and uses them as a lens on the problems posed for maintaining seafood resources in the twenty-first century. Each serves as a different cautionary tale: the Eastern Oyster for over-development of our coastlines, the Gulf Shrimp for competition from globalized commodity markets built on aquaculture, and the Alaskan Salmon for American ignorance of the source of their seafood. The book is brisk and readable despite the bleak picture it paints and touches on a wide array of subjects including global labor markets, climate change, urban planning, and consumer tastes. Greenberg concludes in outlining some possibilities for progress and makes the case that positive change has already begun, but the changes are still small and the road ahead seems very, very long.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/921934890">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0143127438/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 10:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/10/19/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/10/19/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Expedience in Sourdough</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p><a href="http://amzn.to/2ggt6NK"><img src="/images/2017/sourdough-cover.jpg" class="book-cover" alt="Sourdough cover" /></a></p>

<p>Robin Sloan sets his recent novel <a href="http://amzn.to/2ggt6NK"><em>Sourdough</em></a> in a familiar present or near-future San Francisco where startup culture sits uneasily on top of previous incarnations of the city’s many subcultures. The portrayal is a nuanced mix of sympathy and critique that can only come through familiarity. It is enthusiastic, but skeptical.</p>

<p>One small choice struck me in connection to this balance, and I think Sloan’s solution to this problem provides an interesting perspective on the role of online, networked defaults in our lives.</p>

<p>With the proliferation of corporate-owned, private online platforms and tools and their de facto status as default services, verisimilitude in fiction requires some acknowledgment that these branded services exist, but aesthetics or politics may compel us not to use specific names.</p>

<p>Sloan’s characters use “an <strong>expedient</strong> online retailer” or “the <strong>expedient</strong> image-based social network”. This construction sidesteps the datedness of brandname references while acknowledging the ubiquity of these services. More interestingly, I think, it deflates the power of the brands in a more subtle way than some of the more stridently anti-corporate formulations I have seen. It says “we have come to rely on the services these companies provide, but we need not care if these specific instances survive.”</p>

<p>This concept of ‘expedience’ encapsulates a lot of my recent hesitation around closed, branded, and/or privately-owned online services. So much of their strength comes from their convenience and ubiquity. They are the choice of people who don’t have the time or inclination to dig deeper in that area; they are sometimes actually better or even exceptional, but frequently they are simply expedient.</p>

<p>My primary reaction to this technique while reading was on these aesthetic grounds, but it strikes me that there is also some product design guidance here as well. People making services that want to deliver more to those who care need to focus on being sufficiently permeable to the expedient choice to defray the cost of connoisseurship. Expedience can trump excellence even for enthusiasts when it comes to networked platforms.Manton Reece’s goals for <a href="http://micro.blog">micro.blog</a>, for example, seem to track with this, though he still has a long way to go to make it a reality. It’s something I intend to keep in mind while I think about product ideas that are services in areas with existing expedient choices. I am happy to make things that addresses niches that appeal to specific tastes and interests, but I need to be careful not to make it too difficult to balance peculiar enthusiasms with expedient pragmatisms.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 13:05:01 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/10/13/expedience.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/10/13/expedience.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Famous Tex-Mex Quesos</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I pre-ordered <a href="http://www.homesicktexan.com">Lisa Fain</a>’s new <a href="http://amzn.to/2y67xqu"><em>Queso!</em></a> cookbook months ago when I heard about it and it arrived today. I opened it to this list of five notable Tex-Mex restaurant quesos.</p>

<p>This list is correct. I am enthusiastic about the book.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Bob Armstrong Dip</strong> – Matt’s El Rancho – Austin, TX</li>
  <li><strong>Felix Queso</strong> – Felix’s (and El Patio) – Houston, TX</li>
  <li><strong>José’s Dip</strong> – Molina’s - Houston, TX</li>
  <li><strong>Kerbey Queso</strong> – Kerbey Lane – Austin, TX</li>
  <li><strong>Mag Mud</strong> – Magnolia Cafe – Austin, TX</li>
</ul>


    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 16:37:01 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/26/famous-tex-mex-quesos.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/26/famous-tex-mex-quesos.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: September 23, 2017</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <h3 id="links">Links</h3>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://idlewords.com/2017/09/anatomy_of_a_moral_panic.htm"><strong>Anatomy of a Moral Panic—Idle Words—Maciej Ceglowski</strong></a>: Maciej is one of my favorite deflators of tech-industry-related hysterias and enthusiasms. His dissection of <a href="https://www.channel4.com/news/potentially-deadly-bomb-ingredients-on-amazon">this recent story</a> about Amazon shopping algorithms recommending bomb-making materials is a succinct indictment of the consequences of click-bait journalism and tech credulity.</li>
</ul>


    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0785197028/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Ryan North and Erica Henderson. <i>The Unbeatable Squirrel Girl, vol. 1: Squirrel Power</i>. New York: Marvel, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I’m glad to have read this after taking a bit of a break from reading comics. The art style and writing tone are well-paired, and leaning into the silliness of the Squirrel Girl character design by having her face off with Galactus of all villains was a great instinct.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/962423243">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0785197028/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00AXIZ464/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Tash Aw. <i>Five Star Billionaire: A Novel</i>. New York: Spiegel & Grau, 2014.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The Shanghai setting is as much a character as any of the five protagonists—all of them Malaysian transplants who followed different paths to China—that circle each other in this novel. The narrative is interspersed with passages from a self-help/business-achievement memoir that tracks the trajectories of each of the main characters and eventually exposes the isolation and dissatisfaction inherent in the lives prescribed by the worldview in these books and in the rapid urbanization and globalization of China. The end felt a bit pat. I would have accepted less wrapping up, but there were a lot of open threads to tie together.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/884930598">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00AXIZ464/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B06XC41K6G/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Robin Sloan. <i>Sourdough: A Novel</i>. New York: MCD Books, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Robin Sloan may be my favorite active novelist. Reading <em>Sourdough</em> has made me want to pick up <a href="/2015/06/28/weekly-reading.html"><em>Mr. Penumbra’s 24-Hour Bookstore</em></a> for a third time. The quirky, questing enthusiasm of his characters and the narrow balance he strikes between small moments of magic tucked into a very recognizable quotidian present hit my pleasure-reading tastes squarely.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/968638708">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B06XC41K6G/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 18:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/23/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/23/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Columbus Podcasts</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>A list of podcasts associated with Columbus, OH that participated in the 2017 Independents’ Day Festival</p>

<ul>
  <li>Columbus! Something New</li>
  <li>ACES Radio</li>
  <li>Idea Foundry</li>
  <li>The Sounds of Bustown</li>
  <li>The Confluence Cast</li>
  <li>What’s The Deal With Creativity</li>
</ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 10:40:01 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/21/columbus-podcasts.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/21/columbus-podcasts.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>The Sound of the Belgian Underground</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>Subbacultcha is curating a festival at Ancienne Belgique next year called ‘The Sound of the Belgian Underground’. This is a list of participants.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://soundcloud.com/halogenmusicgroup/afia-fuck">Afia</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WkInnXlNMjk">AIR LQD</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=A-ys3sRKGd0">Crowd Of Chairs</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4cNZ4Ca5o1A">Le77</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1FFbtHaqhWM">Sale Gosse</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://soundcloud.com/midlifemusic/kassett-u-01-b277-w-samuelspaniel">Kassett</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vW-OsP6vAXA">Vaal</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://soundcloud.com/christine-denamur">Christine Denamur</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vzGa94YCl68">Wolvennest</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://soundcloud.com/1000amen/kassett-charme-ft-rin">Golin</a></li>
</ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 09:15:01 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/21/sound-of-the-belgian-underground.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/21/sound-of-the-belgian-underground.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Dave Winer on Misunderstanding and Design</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>Sometimes when people misunderstand a product or feature they give you ideas for how it might work or for another product or feature. Creativity sometimes comes just from not knowing something. Another reason it’s important to listen, you never know how new ideas will arrive.</p>

  <p>– <cite><a href="http://scripting.com/2017/09/08.html#a112822">Dave Winer</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 15:13:01 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/14/winer-on-misunderstanding.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/14/winer-on-misunderstanding.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Superheroes, Pilates, and Autotune</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00DG292XK/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Sean Howe. <i>Marvel Comics: The Untold Story</i>. New York: Harper Perennial, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I’ve always been interested in having a greater understanding of the long trajectory of both the history of the Marvel story universe and of Marvel as a business, having followed comic books for only about a year as a teenager but enjoyed being generally aware of the current set of ”important” books in recent years. This chronicle is incredibly detailed which made it a little slow going when I didn’t have any outside familiarity with the material, but it was well done and interesting. I’m glad to have read it and enjoyed it, even when I moved slowly through some eras.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/963603235">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00DG292XK/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01N43SQER/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Harri Angell. <i>Pilates for Runners</i>. London: Bloomsbury Sport, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>There’s just enough theory here to make the reading worthwhile, but the main focus of the book is clear descriptions of mat Pilates exercises and sample routines targeted at runners’ strength and flexibility needs.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/957021150">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01N43SQER/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B019CBM636/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jayce Clayton. <i>Uproot: Travels in Twenty-First-Century Music and Global Digital Culture</i>. New York: Farrar Straus & Giroux, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p><em>Uproot</em> is an incredibly compelling blend of artist memoir, cultural criticism, and music and travel writing that does an amazing job of addressing the influence of digital media formats, recording and production tools, broadcasting and performance technologies, and more on listening, performance, and composition in music today. I share Clayton’s affinity for some of the regional styles he explores and am completely unaware of others, so I look forward to following through on those.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/953157396">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B019CBM636/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B010ZXKDBC/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Andie Mitchell. <i>Eating in the Middle: A Mostly Wholesome Cookbook</i>. New York: Clarkson Potter, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The organizing principle of this book is to find ways to adjust cooking techniques and substitute ingredients in comfort foods to make them a bit more healthful while still being satisfying. Many of the recipes themselves are good, but the biggest help for me was as an exercise in finding ways to make adjustments to lower calories in other recipes.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/991055834">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B010ZXKDBC/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B002VUFKDY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Daniel Suarez. <i>Freedom</i>. New York: Signet, 2010.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I enjoy this series, but continue to wish there was more focus on world building and less on action. I was struck reading this by how it prefigures some of the ideas Cory Doctorow explored in <a href="http://tinaja.computer/2017/05/24/recent-reading.html"><em>Walkaway</em></a> although without the same degree of rigorous analysis. It makes for more of a page-turner, but also it is fundamentally a less ambitious work.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/617551227">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B002VUFKDY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 15:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/11/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/11/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mac Apps I Use</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>This week I kept a running list of the applications I used on my Mac at least once.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://flyingmeat.com/acorn/">Acorn 6</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://alfredapp.com">Alfred 3</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://atom.io">Atom</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://bear-writer.com">Bear</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.busymac.com/busycal/">BusyCal</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.google.com/chrome/browser/desktop/index.html">Chrome</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.devontechnologies.com/products/devonthink/devonthink-pro-office.html">DEVONthink Pro Office</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://products.office.com/en-US/excel">Excel</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://flexibits.com/fantastical">Fantastical 2</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox">Firefox</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://gitkraken.com">GitKraken</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://gitup.co">GitUp</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://hyper.is">Hyper</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.apple.com/itunes/download/">iTunes</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.kaleidoscopeapp.com">Kaleidoscope</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/kindle-dbs/fd/kcp">Kindle</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://freron.com">MailMate</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.mamp.info/en/mamp-pro/">MAMP Pro</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://manytricks.com/moom/">Moom</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://noteplan.co">NotePlan</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus">OmniFocus 2</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.omnigroup.com/omnioutliner">OmniOutliner 5</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1548768604/twitterrific-for-mac-project-phoenix">Phoenix</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://matthewpalmer.net/rocket/">Rocket</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.apple.com/safari/">Safari</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://slack.com">Slack</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.acqualia.com/soulver/">Soulver</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://bananafishsoftware.com/products/spillo/">Spillo</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://panic.com/transmit/">Transmit 5</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://typora.io">Typora</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://tableflipapp.com">TableFlip</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://eternalstorms.at/yoink/Yoink_-_Simplify_and_Improve_Drag_and_Drop_on_your_Mac/Yoink_-_Simplify_drag_and_drop_on_your_Mac.html">Yoink</a></li>
</ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/08/31/mac-apps.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/08/31/mac-apps.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Bitcoin, Spider Jerusalem, and API Design</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01D8KFX9Q/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Nathaniel Popper. <i>Digital Gold: Bitcoin and the Inside Story of the Misfits and Millionaires Trying to Reinvent Money</i>. New York: Harper, 2015.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Listened to this as an audiobook over an incredibly long time in small, disjointed pieces, so I am not certain that I have the most fair impression of it. Some interesting detail here and there on early Bitcoin ventures, but a lot on the Silk Road felt like it had been done elsewhere and in general it felt like there was a lack of much analytical value. Helpful as a descriptive timeline for readers looking for that detail, but my impression was that wasn’t much of a point of view here.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/953442959">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01D8KFX9Q/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00HO12CRW/ref=nosim/latin031-20">J. Michael Orenduff. <i>The Pot Thief Who Studied Einstein</i>. The Pot Thief Mysteries, no. 3. New York: Open Road, 2011.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The third installment in this light, easy-reading cozy mystery series. More of the same, really, but I continue to enjoy the Albuquerque setting while reading from Berlin.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/889943664">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00HO12CRW/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0692232699/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Phil Sturgeon. <i>Build APIs You Won’t Hate: Everyone and Their Dog Wants an API, So You Should Probably Learn How to Build Them</i>. Self-published, 2015.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The earlier chapters of this book focus more on design and theory and were very helpful for someone coming to API design without a lot of confidence that they even know the right questions to ask. Just having read these three or four early chapters would have been sufficient for me to be more comfortable venturing off on my own. The demonstration code in the more practically-oriented ermainder of the book is in PHP and assumes some of the author’s own libraries for which there are not necessarily ready equivalents in other languages, but it is nonetheless clearly written enough that it should be helpful demonstration for any reader.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/990938288">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0692232699/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B009POHIE8/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Warren Ellis. <i>Transmetropolitan, Vol. 1: Back on the Street</i>. New York: DC Comics, 2009.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I have read so much other Warren Ellis and have never read his most famous series. This first volume was a blast and coincidentally fell nicely in line with my accidental streak of reading late 80s and 90s stuff counter culture and hacker culture stuff recently. Interesting unexpected resonances with today’s media and political climate two decades later.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/772553475">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B009POHIE8/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B0087ORPFO/ref=nosim/latin031-20">John Sandford. <i>The Empress File</i>. New York: Berkley Books, 1991.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The second installment in a late 80s and early 90s thriller series about a computer penetration specialist and painter, this time running a con on a political cabal in a small Southern city. More tightly written than the <a href="/2017/07/14/recent-reading.html">first one</a>, but there was less emphasis on the computer exploits that provided some of the nostalgic interest of the first one.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/229231956">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B0087ORPFO/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 14:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/07/26/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/07/26/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>