<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>La Tinaja</title>
<description>My name is Brian Jones. These are my notes on topics including books, publishing, tech, and history.</description>
<link>http://tinaja.computer</link>
<atom:link href="http://tinaja.computer/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Wine and Dystopia</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307270181/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Martin Walker. <i>The Dark Vineyard</i>. New York: Random House, 2010.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is the second book in this series about a small-town police chief in the Dordogne. I’ve already started the third. These are effective, light English-countryside-style murder mysteries recast in a French setting. The central drama in this episode ties together anti-GMO activism and the international wine market. A satisfying quick read.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/679311915">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307270181/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250228581/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Cory Doctorow. <i>Radicalized</i>. New York: Tor Books, 2019.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This volume collects four novellas around themes of radicalization in contemporary and near future U.S. politics. The first story about refugees in subsidized housing enacting resistance through hacking their DRM-crippled home appliances will likely be the most familiar for those who have read Doctorow’s other work. It is also the most affirming in its way. The final installment about a group of survivalist preppers was a surprise for me because its anti-hero central character serves to demonstrate the futility of his ideology on a cul-de-sac off the main path of history, reversing Doctorow’s typical rhetorical tactics.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1091292144">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250228581/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1940535174/ref=nosim/latin031-20">L.E. Hall. <i>Katamari Damacy</i>. Los Angeles: Boss Fight Books, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I have enjoyed all of the Boss Fight Books volumes I have read. The approach for this one is pretty straightforward reportage on the process of how the game came to be and some biographical explication of its creator’s unique trajectory through the tradition-bound Japanese videogame industry. It is an interesting investigation of the difficulties posed in trying to work outside of genre conventions in videogame design and of the benefits of whimsy and constraints in design. While some of the volumes in this series can stand alone, this one may be of most interest to readers who have at least some familiarity with the game.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1083464714">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1940535174/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/194053500X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Ken Baumann. <i>EarthBound</i>. Los Angeles: Boss Fight Books, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This was the founding entry in the Boss Fight Books series and lays a good foundation for the idiosyncratic editorial approach of the series. Baumann weaves the narrative of the game with memoir, connecting topics ranging from a small-town upbringing to the career of a child actor to a life-threatening health scare. A third, less-continuous narrative thread follows the game development process itself and provides opportunity for Baumann to interrogate the relationship of creators and consumers of games in the same way that the primary thread connects the way fictional narratives can help us to process the trajectories of our own experience. I think the result is a little uneven—there are parts that feel like they reach a little too far in an immature way. However, there was far less writing about videogames in this mode available when this book was written, and as a demonstration of stretching the boundaries of what one can write about videogames, it’s a great first step in this now five-year-old series.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/882441227">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/194053500X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 08:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/06/05/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/06/05/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Detectives in Exotic Places</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1616957336/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Ed Lin. <i>Incensed</i>. New York: Soho Crime, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>As the second book in a series, I wish this had trusted me a bit more to have retained the characterizations and the world-building from the first. There are more asides reminding the reader who characters and of past events than feel necessary. I will be curious to see if that persists in the third installment. The protagonist remains a bit of a cipher, but what in the first felt like characterization, with extended exposure perhaps starts to feel simply shallow. All that said, I still enjoyed reading it. I like the setting and Lin builds suspense effectively. My criticisms, I think, come from feeling like these books could be even more than they are, rather than feeling them to be failures on their own terms.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/934676725">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1616957336/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/014312305X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Keith McCafferty. <i>The Royal Wulff Murders</i>. New York: Penguin, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Sean Stranahan is a painter, fisherman, and former private detective that has moved to Montana from New England. When a dead body is found in the river, he gets pulled into the investigation by two women: the local sheriff and a femme fatale in the form of a touring singer. The setting is well-done and is not incidental to the mystery at play which pulls together a strands of politics in the contemporary American West. I would have enjoyed even more of that, but I was pleasantly surprised to have any.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/796931807">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/014312305X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307270173/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Martin Walker. <i>Bruno, Chief of Police</i>. New York: Random House, 2010.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I have been on a trend of reading light mysteries for their escapist settings recently, and this is another one. Bruno is a police chief for a small village in the Dordogne who has an appreciation for food and for the cast of unusual small-town characters in the village. In these ways it serves as a predictable and comfortable cozy mystery. The murder at the center of the story, however, is itself rather gruesome, and the legacies of colonialism and World War II that frame the conflict offer some more difficult moral dilemmas than in the typical cozy read. There are a lot of books in this series, and I think I’ll continue with it.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1000491949">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307270173/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1557512087/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Nick Bilton. <i>American Kingpin: The Epic Hunt for the Criinal Mastermind Behind the Silk Road</i>. New York: Portfolio, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I had the same problem with this book as I did with Nick Bilton’s Twitter book. The scene-by-scene action is well-executed and maintains a page-turning propulsion, but I’m frequently frustrated by the absence of any explicit analytical framework. This is an interesting explanation of the development of the Silk Road and of the investigation that brought it down, but has relatively little to say about the social context that created the moment in which the Silk Road could thrive. I understand that the broader market for these business and technology book-length profiles favors this approach over a more academic one. I look forward to a future generation of books on these subjects that can afford to be less broad in their appeal.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1027541424">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1557512087/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2019 03:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/05/11/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/05/11/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Web Development on an iPad Pro</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>To get the recommendations out of the way up front, the tools I use in the workflow I describe below are:</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://m.do.co/c/f771f7c968c9">DigitalOcean</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://ngrok.com">Ngrok</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.blink.sh">Blink</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.textasticapp.com">Textastic</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://workingcopyapp.com">Working Copy</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://apps.pdyn.net/inspect/">Inspect</a></li>
</ul>

<hr />

<p>I have been experimenting with doing web development on my iPad Pro. The main pain point has been to find a set of tools that allow me to work with a development server environment and other command line tooling (e.g., a Node.js server, a Sass preprocessor, a database server, or a static site generator) instead of static HTML files. On previous occasions I have managed to work out a few pieces of the puzzle, but never in a way that was simple enough to feel like anything more than a parlor trick. With the setup outlined below, however, I’m finally doing work on a regular basis with an array of different technology stacks and limited friction with an iPad Pro.</p>

<h3 id="the-server">The Server</h3>

<p>I have been using <a href="https://m.do.co/c/f771f7c968c9">DigitalOcean</a> to run a light-weight development server, but <a href="https://linode.com">Linode</a> or any other cloud hosting provider would do the trick.</p>

<p>To connect to the server, I use the <a href="https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mosh_(software)">Mosh shell</a> with the <a href="https://www.blink.sh">Blink</a> app. In contrast to SSH, Mosh is designed to maintain a session over intermittent and slow connections. Mosh does this by requiring a server component to be installed on your server so that the responsibility for maintaining the session’s state is not only on the client end. On iOS, this has the added consequence of allowing a Mosh session to stay alive even when Blink is not the active app (or iOS removes it from memory entirely.) With SSH, I would likely have to make a new connection every time I returned to the terminal from doing work in my text editor.</p>

<p>The reason for the cloud server is to be able to run build tools and a ‘local’ development server, neither of which can be done on the iPad itself. However, running a development server at <code class="highlighter-rouge">localhost</code> in the cloud doesn’t do me a lot of good when I want to visit it in a web browser from my iPad.</p>

<p><a href="https://ngrok.com">Ngrok</a> allows me to set up a tunnel with a public URL to my localhost server. So I can start, for example, an <a href="https://expressjs.com">Express</a> or <a href="https://jekyllrb.com">Jekyll</a> server in one Mosh session and then start ngrok in another. Ngrok will show me a public URL in the style of  <code class="highlighter-rouge">https://&lt;subdomain&gt;.ngrok.io</code> which I can then visit in Safari to view my changes. This bit of glue allows me to use a cloud server the same way I would use a local development environment.</p>

<h3 id="editing">Editing</h3>

<p>My favorite coding text editor on iOS is <a href="https://www.textasticapp.com">Textastic</a>. It has been continuously updated since the very early days of iOS, making it both robust and well-tuned to the interaction paradigms of the iOS platform.</p>

<p><a href="https://workingcopyapp.com">Working Copy</a> is a sort of central dispatch for this whole process. It is ostensibly a git client, but provides so much more functionality than that classification implies.</p>

<p>First, Working Copy can serve as a document provider, allowing me to edit my files in Textastic easily. Having created or cloned a repository in Working Copy, in Textastic tap “Open File or Folder…” under the “External Files and Folders” header in the sidebar to bring up the iOS document picker interface. You should see Working Copy in the list of Locations on the left side. In the top right, tap “Select,” then tap a repository, and finally tap “Open” in the top right to open that repository as a folder in Textastic. Now, when you edit these files in Textastic, Working Copy will be aware of the changes.</p>

<p>So now you are tracking your changes made with Textastic in Working Copy and will be able to commit and push them to your git remote. This is Working Copy’s primary purpose, but there’s another piece of functionality in Working Copy that makes it essential for working with a remote development server. With the <a href="https://workingcopyapp.com/manual/ssh-upload">SSH Upload</a> feature, you can link a repository to a remote server location and have Working Copy watch for changes and upload them to that destination.</p>

<p>To summarize, the editing workflow is: edit files in Textastic; switch to Working Copy so that the app activates, notices the changed files, and syncs them to the remote server; and open a browser to view your updated code running on the server.</p>

<p>The only catch with this process is that the SSH Upload feature is not immediately easy to discover. When viewing a repo in Working Copy, you have to open the iOS share sheet and find the ‘SSH Upload’ action. Tapping that will open a panel at the top of the sidebar to configure a remote connection (by password or SSH key.) This interface is not exposed until SSH Upload has been activated for a particular repo, but once it has been configured, it will not need to be reactivated for subsequent sessions.</p>

<h3 id="previewing">Previewing</h3>

<p>With an Ngrok tunnel running on my development server, I can interact with the development version of my code with Safari or any other browser on the iPad.</p>

<p>When I’m doing large-grained, additive work where my main interest is in maintaining forward momentum, I usually just use Safari to make sure that the large scale changes aren’t resulting in any big surprises. However, a lot of my time involves testing or polishing work that requires the console or to be able to inspect CSS rules. In those cases, <a href="https://apps.pdyn.net/inspect/">Inspect</a> is the best option for in-browser developer tools I’ve found so far.</p>

<p>The desktop environment has strongly shaped the received interface paradigms of in-browser developer tools, and Inspect sometimes struggles in wrangling this complexity for the touch environment. There is room for improvement here—both in Inspect itself and perhaps in the creation of more focused and fine-tuned apps designed for touch—but it’s certainly possible on iOS to do the vast majority of the things I’m doing on a regular basis with developer tools on the desktop even if it’s not always as convenient.</p>

<hr />

<p>The vast majority of these puzzle pieces have been available for quite a while now. My two recent discoveries that have made everything click into place are Ngrok and the SSH Upload feature of Working Copy. Together they get my code changes onto a live server and back out into a web browser with little enough friction that I feel free to rely on my iPad in situations when its convenience and portability would be useful.</p>


    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/04/27/ipad-web-dev.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/04/27/ipad-web-dev.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Coupland on biography and archival abundance</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>On the other hand, here’s the thing: it doesn’t matter whether I, as a biographer, drive to the civic library and hang out with the reference librarians all day—in the end, I’d end up with the same information that I’d have found here at home, online. Would the bricks-and-mortar research come with a pedigree? Would I need to show Chevron gas slips and document my mileage to score points? This throws the notion of “biography” into a new light. We can all hopscotch from link to link to link—it’s what most people do now, anyway. So Why write a biography? Maybe to get a sense of how it felt to be someone else in a different time. Maybe to cast new light on an old subject. Maybe to learn new ways of thinking. Maybe to try to enter an already vanishing mode of perceiving the past, the notion that a landscape is best viewed with a single source of light—the sun, one light bulb, a lone candle, a lone writer—so that all the shadows and highlights are true to each other.</p>

  <p>– <cite>From Douglas Coupland’s <i>Marshall McLuhan: You Know Nothing of My Work!</i></cite></p>
</blockquote>

<p>My <a href="https://dayoneapp.com">Day One</a> journal tells me that I clipped this quotation four years ago today. I was doing a lot of reading in the middle of the night with a newborn child and a recently minted PhD and wondering what kind of writing I might be able to do outside of an academic context.</p>

<p>I still have no idea. Oops.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 09:47:01 +0000</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/04/19/biography.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/04/19/biography.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Tech Criminals and Dieting</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B074ZGR8FR/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Christopher Payne and Rob Barnett. <i>The Economists’ Diet: The Surprising Formula for Losing Weight and Keeping It Off</i>. New York: Gallery Books, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I heard about this from <a href="https://www.burntfen.com">Richard Littauer’s newsletter</a>. It has the frequent mass-market non-fiction problem of feeling like the concept is being stretched to fill the format, but sometimes there is something to be said for being forced to sit with the repetition of a concept that is intended to be behavior changing. There is a difference between understanding an idea and internalizing it, and I can understand that I may have internalized more of the very straightforward ideas presented here by having them repeated to me than I might have had I allowed myself to skim for the bullet points. That said, it is possible to boil this worldview down to some very basic ideas: choose a single metric (weight) and measure it consistently (daily), eat less, and limit variety as a response to the problems of eating in an age of abundance. The authors’ persepective comes from pursuing pretty aggressive weight loss from a background of relatively poor eating habits. My interest is primarily in maintaining a consistent weight (or perhaps light weight loss). With a relatively aggressive running regimen, I have a history of eating large portions on days of long runs. This way of eating becomes habit during periods of relatively extreme exertion and then persists into lighter phases of my training schedule. The focus here on correlating measurement and observation to restrictions on food quantity I think can be helpful in helping to smooth this pattern out.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1017750789">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B074ZGR8FR/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/152473165X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">John Carreyrou. <i>Bad Blood: Secrets and Lies in a Silicon Valley Startup</i>. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I listened to this as an audiobook and found it very interesting. It is (unsurprisingly) the best bit of media I have encountered on the Theranos debacle. I particularly appreciated the matter-of-fact presentation that allows the words and actions of the Theranos leadership to speak for themselves. There’s little benefit to rehashing the general outline of this well-covered story here, but this book is definitely essential reading for anyone with more than a passing interest in the subject.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1089195731">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/152473165X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/178108520X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Antony Johnston. <i>Stealing Life</i>. Oxford: Abaddon Books, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>It took me a little bit to get interested in this because the setting and characters felt a little generic and shallow, but it becomes clear that the focus is on building tightly constructed thriller. Approached from that angle, this is an engrossing, quick read. You can feel a very strong intentionality in the planning and plotting that I think belies Johnston’s experience as a comics writer.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1064672356">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/178108520X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0399590412/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Evan Ratliff. <i>The Mastermind: Drugs, Empire, Murder, Betrayal</i>. New York: Random House, 2019.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Unfortunately I listened to this as an audiobook while participating in the Rotterdam Marathon which I did not finish, so I had some negative associations with returning to it to finish it up. It’s a very compelling story, and I can identify with Ratliff’s curiosity about Le Roux’s trajectory having also come of age at a similar time in the history of the Internet with a similar interest in computers and a similar distrust of authority. So much of Le Roux’s behavior is horrific, but Ratliff does an admirable job of exploring him as a figure in the context of a particular set of technological, geopolitical, and economic realities rather than simply indulging in a sensational account of his transgressions. Similarly, the epilogue presents the ephemerality of Le Roux’s power and the smallness of his end in tension with the breadth of the fallout for others while avoiding the simplicity of a straightforward tale of a moral comeuppance.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1048445404">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0399590412/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 08:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/04/15/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/04/15/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Just Use a Database</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I am in the middle of writing some scripts to migrate a bunch of data stored as JSON into a SQLite database as well as a small front-end application for visualizations and CRUD-style operations on that data.</p>

<p>I started with JSON because we wanted to get moving quickly, and with JSON we could be hand-generating and -correcting data records while we waited for better tools to get developed. My partner on the project is also less technical, and the idea was that a human-readable format would be more likely to make him available for data entry while we waited for me to build better tools (or if those tools never came.)</p>

<p>I also thought it would be a good idea to always have our data in a plain text format so that it could be easily archived and shared regardless of the technological state the project was left in. The worry was with an ambitious, but unfunded, side project we would potentially hit a wall at some point, and I did not want to be left with a bunch of work to do to then expose our data to be reusable by someone else.</p>

<p>That was a mistake.</p>

<p>Working around the constraints involved in keeping our data in this way has almost certainly added up to more work than was theoretically saved by not building the tools to work with a database. And now I’m building those tools anyways. And in the event that we do stop working on the project, the work involved in coming up with a schema for a set of JSON (or similar) files and the output scripts to generate them would not be so big a deal.</p>

<p>I’ve learned the lesson again: just use a relational database.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/03/28/just-use-a-database.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/03/28/just-use-a-database.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Escaping on an iPad with no Esc key</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I’ve recently been connecting to a DigitalOcean droplet with the mosh shell using the <a href="https://www.blink.sh">Blink</a> app on my iPad. It’s been a fun way to do some light web development work away from my desk at home without having to lug a lot of gear.</p>

<p>I’m using Apple’s smart folio keyboard for the time-being. It does not have an <code class="highlighter-rouge">Esc</code> key.</p>

<p>I’ve gotten around a lot of my <code class="highlighter-rouge">Esc</code> key muscle memory already (I end up in all caps by accident a lot because <code class="highlighter-rouge">Esc</code> is mapped to <code class="highlighter-rouge">Caps Lock</code> on my Mac), but I found myself in vim on the server this morning and realized I had no idea how to leave insert mode without an <code class="highlighter-rouge">Esc</code> key.</p>

<p>Turns out <code class="highlighter-rouge">Ctrl</code> + <code class="highlighter-rouge">[</code> sends the same ASCII code that <code class="highlighter-rouge">Esc</code> does. Now I know.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 07:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/03/14/escape.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/03/14/escape.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Surfing Cops and Imaginary Places</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307953890/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jay Caspian Kang. <i>The Dead Do Not Improve</i>. New York: Hogarth, 2012.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I have a particular affinity for California outsider detective characters, so even when I thought that was all that was going on here, I was excited for it. I like Kang’s cynical sense of humor, and we’re of similar ages, tastes, and worldviews as far as I can tell from what I’ve seen of him in media (the book’s title is a Silver Jews reference, after all). I was pleasantly surprised that there is more here than just the detective story. The critiques of Bay Area- and Silicon Valley-facilitated celebrity and attention culture and limp liberalism that today may feel a little obvious were prescient, but no less true, when the book came out. Conversely, the concern with mass violence is very much of its era, but unfortunately no less important today. The book is simultaneously a page-turner and a little bit grotesque, which is an unusual combination.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/802338219">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307953890/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1635061539/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Andrew Caldecott. <i>Rotherweird</i>. London: Jo Fletcher Books, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I took a very long time to get through this. I probably should have dropped it as it never turned the corner for me, but the premise kept me waiting to be hooked by it. The setting is a town where the study of history and contact with the outside world are prohibited. I kept waiting for more interesting consequences of this tension to be born out and for the cast of strange characters reminiscent of an English countryside mystery to yield more interest, but the resolution comes instead through magical and fantastical conflict that is simply not my taste. I confess it may have been a mistake that I listened to it as an audiobook instead of reading it. It’s possible that some of the detail I was hoping for would have been apparent if I had had time to sit with it and tease it out, rather than being pulled along at the narrator’s pace.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1050443848">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1635061539/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 07:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/03/14/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/03/14/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Cartels, Baking, and Kleptocracy</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B07FHLQ2DD/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Michael Lewis. <i>The Coming Storm</i>. Audiobook. Seattle, WA: Audible Studios, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I appreciate Michael Lewis’s Trump-era focus on the centrality of bureaucratic competence (or lack thereof) to American successes and the unfortunate lack of public awareness of its dysfunction in the shadow of the Trump administrations more sensational failures, embarrassments, and abuses. The primary focus here has the particularly Trumpian theme of kleptocracy at the National Weather Service. It’s material that has now been made available elsewhere, but in this iteration was produced as an Audible-exclusive audiobook. Lewis reads his own work, and his natural storyteller’s gift comes through as well in his voice and delivery as it does in his writing.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B07FHLQ2DD/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/"><i>Full Stack React</i>. San Francisco, CA: Fullstack.io, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This e-book is a good, pragmatic walkthrough for building a web app with React, Node.js, and GraphQL. The focus is on React, and the pacing is the best in the sections most-focused on React. To the (limited) extent that there is some more theoretical material explaining the practical examples, this is similarly the most useful in the React sections. Working with this book has been a worthwhile exercise, but the most instructional value here is definitely dedicated to React and the sections on the rest of the stack will probably need to be supplemented from elsewhere</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B07BLGZVZX/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Linda Andersson. <i>Homemade Bread</i>. New York: Skyhorse Publishing, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Andersson is a Swedish food journalist who seems to focus on practical home baker oriented recipes. This English translation of her book is very direct in that there are quantities that appear in pretty unusual quantities in terms of imperial measurements. I might have preferred to have the original metric measurements so that I could do conversions myself or not as convenient. The recipes themselves, though, are very useful. Lots of Swedish basics I will enjoy experimenting with and some good practical advice on how to adjust basic recipes to personal tastes. In my experience, baking books either pursue a theoretical that is only useful for relatively advanced bakers or present basic recipes with no elaboration on how they work and how they might be altered. Andersson’s more open approach to instruction at a technical level appropriate to baking simple family-oriented basics has been very useful to me.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1000049545">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B07BLGZVZX/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0525436510/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Don Winslow. <i>The Cartel</i>. New York: Vintage Crime, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>We received this book as a Christmas gift from a friend who confessed it had wrecked his winter grading schedule. It works on an impressive scale, exploring the fallout of the U.S. war on drugs in Mexico over the course of about 15 years and from Guatemala to Matamoros to San Diego, but with the heart of its narrative in Juaréz at the peak of the violence there. It’s both engrossing and appalling in its action sequences while managing to be mostly sensitive to the horrible human consequences of U.S.-driven anti-drug policy. It is fundamentally an entertainment, but its political engagement feels authentic.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1008999844">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0525436510/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/02/28/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/02/28/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Oddments</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I’ve set up a new small web page I’m calling <a href="https://oddments.brianjon.es">Oddments</a> to collect links to and information about projects I’m working on.</p>

<p>I’m hoping that having a place to collect these things will provide some motivation to keep building them.</p>

<p>I keep bouncing back and forth on the value of having hobbies and pursuits that generate ephemeral products. On the one hand it is the case that the pressure to conceive of any freetime pursuit as something to be connected to a larger project or to be productized or otherwise commodified is a powerful trap. On the other, my life at the moment makes for such infrequent moments of freedom to play that having leisure pursuits that produce lasting products is a nice reminder that I do in fact have hobbies.</p>

<p>So here is <a href="https://oddments.brianjone.s">Oddments</a>. Let’s hope it keeps growing.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2019/01/26/oddments.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2019/01/26/oddments.html</guid>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>