<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>La Tinaja</title>
<description>My name is Brian Jones. These are my notes on topics including books, publishing, tech, and history.</description>
<link>http://tinaja.computer</link>
<atom:link href="http://tinaja.computer/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Spies and Cooking</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0393254151/ref=nosim/latin031-20">David Ignatius. <i>The Quantum Spy: A thriller</i>. New York: W.W. Norton & Company, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>In theory I like pulpy airport spy thrillers, but am almost always disappointed when I take a chance on one from an unfamiliar author. I don’t feel like I read enough to waste time on ones that aren’t great examples of the form. I listened to an interview with David Ignatius whom I know as a foreign policy journalist. When he revealed he’s also been a spy novelist for most of his career, I decided I should check it out. I will read more. All of the thriller mechanics were solid and engrossing, and the specifics of the world—quantum computing, tech espionage, Big Science bureaucracy—all felt non-stupid.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/985974585">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0393254151/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B004HYHB48/ref=nosim/latin031-20">David Downing. <i>Zoo Station</i>. New York: SoHo Crime, 2007.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The protagonist is a British journalist living and working in late 1930s Berlin. I bought the e-book on a promotion primarily out of interest in the setting. Unfortunately the construction of that setting frequently relies more on the name-dropping of streets and locations more than it does on evoking a feeling. However, the very British espionage thriller technique of having someone adjacent to events—a journalist, in this case—thrust into a cloak and dagger world and the mundane mechanics of negotiating the situation saved it for me. It is the first of a series, and I think I will read more. Even though I was a bit disappointed in the world-building, there were passages that suggest to me that future iterations may improve in that regard as well.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/899965461">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B004HYHB48/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1324002646/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Michael Lewis. <i>The Fifth Risk</i>. New York: W.W. Norton & Company, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is a short book exclusive to Amazon that I listened to as an audio book. Because he is such an efficient storyteller and concise stylist, I find that Michael Lewis’s books work particularly well as audiobooks. This one was an eye-opening analysis of the risks around the Trump administration’s failure to address basic administrative responsibilities across the bureaucracy. Lewis suggests (compellingly) that as abhorrent as the administration’s rhetoric is, the incompetence and lack of interest in basic governance has the potential to be more catastrophic.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1057554927">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1324002646/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/006210330X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Karen Le Billon. <i>French Kids Eat Everything: How Our Family Moved to France, Cured Picky Eating, Banished Snacking, and Discovered 10 Simple Rules for Raising Happy, Healthy Eaters</i>. New York: William Morrow, 2012.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Another iteration in the genre of ‘fish out of water’ parenting experiences, this one tracks the experiences of a Vancouver-born woman married to a Frenchmen when they moved their family of four to the small village in Brittany where he grew up. It adheres to genre tropes of possibly exagerrated mea culpas around the author’s personal history of feeding her family in comparison to the enlightened ease with which the French around her succeed at the same task. Nonetheless, Le Billon is an engaging writer, so the stories are fun, and her research into French social science on child development and nutrition was very interesting. I found myself wishing that we had a similar experience in our Belgian school as she did with her French school around the centrality of eating properly (as in eating as a behavior or a pursuit, rather than as a means of nutrition) in early education. It has inspired me to try some of her techniques in bringing unfamiliar Belgian dishes into our dinner routine at home; we have a year to see if it will work out.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/937840155">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/006210330X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B0052RDIGY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Kathleen Finn. <i>The Kitchen Counter Cooking School: How a Few Simple Lessons Transformed Nine Culinary Novices into Fearless Home Cooks</i>. New York: Penguin Books, 2014.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Kathleen Finn was already an accomplished food writer when she embarked on the entrepreneurial task of identifying and remedying many American homemakers’ fear of basic cooking skills and difficult relationships with food and feeding families that results. In its specifics, the book is a memoir of teaching a small cooking basics class to a group of volunteer students and, more generally,  an exploration of the practice of cooking as a form of self-care and a path to self-care and a lamentation of the decline of basic food knowledge as a result of postwar processed food marketing. There are recipes and techniques taken from the class which would be of interest to the reader who was a candidate for her class. I appreciated it mostly for the dicussions of the process of building the class and identifying the needs of her students.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/883321324">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B0052RDIGY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 15:19:00 +0100</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/11/24/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/11/24/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Shipwrecks, Lafayette, Vancouver</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00NDTV6W6/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Robert Kurson. <i>Pirate Hunters: Treasure, Obsession, and the Search for a Legendary Pirate Ship</i>. New York: Random House, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I listened to the bulk of this as an audiobook while running the Louisville Marathon. It’s perhaps not surprising that I wish there were more attention paid to the history, but what is there is actually pretty well done. The exploration of the specific techniques and practice of treasure diving was very interesting. I was less interested in the macho adventure-hero framing around the lives of the main subjects, but I get why it was there.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/966049184">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00NDTV6W6/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/941381351">Rachel Andrew. <i>Get Ready for CSS Grid Layout</i>. Briefs, 1. New York: A Book Apart, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is the first of <a href="https://abookapart.com/">A Book Apart’s</a> Briefs collection of e-book-only publications on short-form topics. I bought this when it came out and never got around to reading it. Now that CSS Grid is more of a reality instead of a developing spec, some of it is a bit outdated, but it is still a very concise and useful introduction to the goals and organizing principles of CSS grid. It makes for a great foundation from which to ramp up quickly through personal experimentation or reading examples online.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/941381351">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307742822/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Guanzhong Chen. <i>The Fat Years</i>. Translated by Michael S. Duke. New York: Anchor Books, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is an interesting satirical speculative fiction story set in very near future China from the perspective of 2011 with some plot elements that give it a little bit of a light science fiction feel. The cultural specificities of the setting necessary to understand the satire would largely have been lost on me without some explanatory notes from the translator responsible for the English language edition. That separation meant it was not always a smooth read, but I am nonetheless glad to have read it.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/976014241">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307742822/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0743243803/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Sarah Vowell. <i>The Partly Cloudy Patriot</i>. New York: Simon & Schuster, 2002.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The audiobook productions of Sarah Vowell’s books are all really great. Reading her own words in her very individual voice presents the dry humor in precisely the right tone, and the readers she gets to present the quotations from primary sources all do great readings. As usual Vowell is particularly interested in popular contemporary understanding of history and perceptions of her subjects. This time she takes the Marquis de Lafayette as her central character to elucidate some of the global connections and the contingencies of the American war of independence that are perhaps not part of most contemporary Americans’ basic understanding of their history.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/49649932">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0743243803/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1596911050/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Douglas Coupland. <i>JPod</i>. Toronto: Random House of Canada, 2006.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Our friends left this on the shelf of their house where we’re living in Gent this year. I hadn’t read it since it came out, but I’m a sucker for Coupland so I picked it up. I remember enjoying it on my first read, but thinking it was less substantial than his other work or not sufficiently additive as a clear successor to <em>Microserfs</em>. Reading it with another decade or so of hindsight, I actually have a great appreciation for it. I come away with the feeling that its slightness is precisely the point—that the characters’ quippiness as apparent substitutions for character traits rather than expressions of them is a consequence of informational ubiquity. Coupland was responding to a post-Google world, but the cultural and spiritual trajectory he identifies seem only more salient in our world that is both post-Google and post-Facebook.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/745958199">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1596911050/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 09:09:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/10/07/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/10/07/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>10 Podcasts You Might Not Listen To</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <ul>
  <li><a href="http://afropop.org/">Afropop Worldwide</a>: A long-tenured public radio show on music from Africa and across the African diaspora</li>
  <li><a href="http://cointalk.show">Coin Talk</a>: An irreverent weekly chat between Aaron Lammer and Jay Kang (and sometimes guests) on goings on in the cryptocurrency world</li>
  <li><a href="http://dankrares.com/">Dank Rares</a>: Interviews with people exploring the possibilities of blockchain technology for market-making in digital art</li>
  <li><a href="http://foodsafetytalk.com/">Food Safety Talk</a>: Commentary on recent news in food safety policy and research combined with shaggy, rambling chat about an array of other subjects between two food safety academics</li>
  <li><a href="https://soundcloud.com/gamething">GAMETHING</a>: Small collages of sound, voiceover, and music created in response to video game experiences</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.southernfoodways.org/gravy-format/gravy-podcast/">Gravy</a>: Tightly produced programs on food and culture topics in the U.S. South from the Southern Foodways Alliance</li>
  <li><a href="https://the.hobbyhorse.club/">Hobby Horse</a>: Matt Haughey interviews people about a personal interest or hobby outside of their field of expertise</li>
  <li><a href="https://toomuchnotenough.site">Too Much Not Enough</a>: Chats between Emma Winston and Darius Kazemi in which they take turns introducing each other to topics of obsessive interest</li>
  <li><a href="https://postlight.com/tag/podcast">Track Changes</a>: Chats between Postlight agency founders Paul Ford and Rich Ziade (and frequently guests) on topics in business and technology</li>
  <li><a href="https://www.20k.org/">Twenty Thousand Hertz</a>: Like a 99% Invisible for sound design</li>
</ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/10/04/podcasts.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/10/04/podcasts.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Murder, Coffee, and Austin</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250056454/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Judith Flanders. <i>A Murder of Magpies</i>. New York: Minotaur Books, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This was a quick, light, and well-written cozy mystery set in the world of London publishing. Scott McNulty recommended it on the <a href="https://www.theincomparable.com/recentlyread/19/">Recently Read</a> podcast, and my feelings about it essentially reflect his. This is very well-executed fun that is absolutely satisfying.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/908085186">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250056454/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307390462/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Maj Sjöwall and Per Wahlöö. <i>Roseanna</i>. Translated by Lois Roth. New York: Vintage Books, 1976 [1967].</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I’ve had these Martin Beck detective stories recommended to me a lot, but finally got around to them having been triggered on Scandinavian detective fiction by something Warren Ellis wrote about Henning Mankell on his mailing list. As it turns out, Mankell contributed a foreword to the edition of <em>Roseanna</em> that I read. He praised similar aspects of Sjöwall’s writing as Ellis had in his, and perhaps not surprisingly these were the traits that I found most enjoyable in this book. There are a patience and a directness in the writing that make the world and characters feel very real. The tension of the police procedural elements are effective precisely by being couched in this realness; there is very little need for the sensational to heighten the stakes. I look forward to reading the rest.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/857990879">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0307390462/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/034580709X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jo Nesbø. <i>The Bat</i>. Translated by Don Bartlett. New York: Vintage, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>It turns out this is the second time I’ve read this. I had the sensation off and on in the beginning that I had, but given that the events of this story serve as flashback material for later novels in the series I wasn’t sure. By the time I was certain, I was hooked again and blazed through the whole thing again. One thing I noticed this time was the use of Australian vocabulary and dialect in the English translation in a way that makes me wonder what was done in the Norwegian original.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/855252507">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/034580709X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1101947314/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Dave Eggers. <i>The Monk of Mokha</i>. New York: Alfred A. Knopf, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I generally prefer Eggers’s narrative nonfiction to his novels. The shifts of frame between analysis and characterization, the global and the individual in the medium allow his powerfully concise expression to shine. He also has a strong instinct for taking real individuals and turning them into emblems of a larger moment. In this case, his protagonist Mokhtar’s story is so very 2018 in its elucidation of the growing inequities of urban America (and the Bay Area specifically), the Sillicon-Valley-ization of American business culture, the immigrant experience in America, the fallout in the rest of the world of the American War on Terror, the evolution of consumer tastes, and so many other. There is so much going on here and yet it reads easy.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1040273087">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1101947314/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/163149287X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">J.R. Helton. <i>Bad Jobs and Poor Decisions: Dispatches from the Working Class: A Memoir</i>. New York: Liveright Publishing Corporation, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I bought this based off of a mention by Will Menaker on the Chapo Trap House podcast last year. His recommendation and most of the reviews focus on the insight into the experience of the American working class in the 1980s. It is an interesting portrait of someone moving from under-paying, over-taxing job to job and bouncing between periods of precarity and relative stability, and Helton is both an empathetic and a direct writer. My primary personal interest, however, was in the setting. Helton’s twenties were spent in the Austin I saw as a kid that made me want to move there. It was an Austin that still existed for the most part as I arrived in the late nineties and disappeared over the course of the seventeen years I lived there. I think a lot of these experiences are still there to be had, but they are definitely by no means still one of the basic default lifestyle choices for Austin twenty-somethings. Though most of my experience did not match some of the extremes in here, it was in its outlines absolutely congruent. I don’t miss quite a bit of that, but it was a nice opportunity for reflection.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/988282578">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/163149287X/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1481497499/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Catherynne M. Valente. <i>Space Opera</i>. New York: Saga Press, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I saw this recommended in a lot of different venues. I think a lot of the enthusiasm for it in the specific venues I saw it has to do with the fluid sexual preferences and gender roles that undergird a lot of the tensions between characters. That was nice to see, but I didn’t really find much revelatory in it. It was just sort of there, which is good in its own way. There’s something to be said for something reaching the point for its presence in a piece of genre fiction to be rather banal. There’s a lot of over-the-top energy and playfulness in the language. Sometimes I found that fun; sometimes I found it a little exhausting. It’s a big long book full of tons of ideas that I enjoyed but was also a little glad to be released from.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/989963881">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1481497499/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0385508603/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Ellen Ullman. <i>The Bug: A Novel</i>. New York: Anchor Books, 2004.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I’ve been meaning to read this for a very long time and having finally gotten around to it regret that it has taken so long. Ullman is such a great, empathetic writer that reading this also highlighted for me how rew novels in which computing plays a major role in plot and setting actually use the computing as a thematic tool. In some ways, this could have been a story about isolation, obsession, and frustrated human communication among people in any occupation; on the other, the peculiar nature of the work of programming and the obsessive tendencies of its practitioners are essential to the protagonist’s individual path to self-destruction. It strikes me that this tension between the universal and the specific would be a defining characteristic of an artful and humane novel.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/56079814">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0385508603/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0785196587/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Tom King, Gabriel Hernandez, Jordie Bellaire, and Clayton Cowles. <i>The Vision, Vol. 2: Little Better than a Beast</i>. New York: Marvel, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I enjoyed the first volume of this quite a bit, but realized in reading the second volume that most of what I got out of it was the world-building and characterization. Once those things had been set, I was less interested in the progression of the narrative and character arcs. There was a little bit too much of a heightened melodrama feel. I recognize that it was interesting and ambitious in the context of mainstream superhero comics, but I think I maybe prefer my unconventional-risk-reads in this format to be subversively fun rather than subversively serious.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1035694563">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0785196587/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2018 09:09:40 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/27/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/27/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Using Object Literals in render() in React</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I’ve been reading the <a href="https://www.fullstackreact.com/">Full Stack React</a> book and came across this neat trick that had never occurred to me before for whatever reason.</p>

<div class="language-javascript highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="p">{{</span>
    <span class="nl">SAVING</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">input</span> <span class="nx">value</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s1">'Saving…'</span> <span class="nx">type</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s1">'submit'</span> <span class="nx">disabled</span> <span class="o">/&gt;</span><span class="p">,</span>
    <span class="nx">SUCCESS</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">input</span> <span class="nx">value</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s1">'Saved!'</span> <span class="nx">type</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s1">'submit'</span> <span class="nx">disabled</span> <span class="o">/&gt;</span><span class="p">,</span>
    <span class="nx">ERROR</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">input</span> <span class="nx">value</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s1">'Save Failed - Retry?'</span> <span class="nx">type</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s1">'submit'</span> <span class="o">/&gt;</span><span class="p">,</span>
    <span class="nx">READY</span><span class="p">:</span> <span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="nx">input</span> <span class="nx">value</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s1">'Submit'</span> <span class="nx">type</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="s1">'submit'</span> <span class="o">/&gt;</span>
<span class="p">}[</span><span class="k">this</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">state</span><span class="p">.</span><span class="nx">_saveStatus</span><span class="p">]}</span>
</code></pre></div></div>

<p>There’s a flag set in the state variable <code class="highlighter-rouge">_saveStatus</code> that will have one of the following values: <code class="highlighter-rouge">SAVING</code>, <code class="highlighter-rouge">SUCCESS</code>, <code class="highlighter-rouge">ERROR</code>, or <code class="highlighter-rouge">READY</code>. Define an object literal tieing each of four different pieces of content (in this case Submit buttons in different states) to one of these keys, and then select the appropriate piece of content by grabbing the value from the appropriate key in that object.</p>

<p>This immediately struck me as a succinct and useful technique. It had never occurred to me myself. I love it when that happens.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 05:19:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/26/object-literal-in-react-render.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/26/object-literal-in-react-render.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Slow Trailers</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I just came across these <a href="http://relax.thegardensbetween.com">”slow trailers”</a> for The Gardens Between today. They are three 10-15 minutes-long animated short films with ambient scores by <a href="https://timshiel.bandcamp.com/">Tim Shiel</a>.</p>

<p>I’ve found them to be compelling and soothing viewing, and I love the idea of them as promotional items. They upend the expected rhythms of online video consumption in a way that seems to pre-figure some of what players of the game can expect.</p>

<div class="youtube-video">&gt;
    <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/73yt3T6ULvM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<div class="youtube-video">
    <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aQZV8vl12_M?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<div class="youtube-video">
    <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gXxCkGcMNVE?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2018 13:49:40 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/24/slow-trailers.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/24/slow-trailers.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Nap Time</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I like taking naps. I don’t like my phone buzzing while I nap. I want to use my phone’s timer to wake me up from my nap. I don’t want to miss phone calls for days because I forgot to turn Do Not Disturb off on my phone.</p>

<p>iOS 12 came out yesterday, and I wanted to give the new <a href="https://www.macstories.net/stories/ios-12-the-macstories-review/7/#shortcuts">Shortcuts</a> system a whirl. I’ve used Workflow <a href="https://tinaja.computer/2015/07/13/comments-in-workflow.html">in the past</a>, but fell off the wagon when it all felt too fiddly. Workflow always felt like a big pile of (amazing) hacky workarounds; the promise of system-level integration now that it has become Shortcuts has me excited to mess around with it again.</p>

<p>So, today instead of taking a nap, I made a ’Nap Time’ shortcut.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="problem">Problem</h3>

<p>I want to take a nap for 30 minutes. I want a timer to wake me up after 30 minutes. I want my phone to be on Do Not Disturb during that time. I want Do Not Disturb off once I’m up.</p>

<hr />

<h3 id="do-not-disturb">Do Not Disturb</h3>

<p>There is a Shortcut action called ‘Set Do Not Disturb’ that allows you to turn on Do Not Disturb until it is turned off manually, until a prescribed time, until you leave the location where the action was invoked, the current event on your calendar ends, a Magic Variable, or the input from the previous shortcut action.</p>

<p>There is no option to set Do Not Disturb for a specified duration. So I will use the ‘Until: Time’ option and give it a time 30 minutes in the future from now.</p>

<p>There’s another action called ‘Date’ that allows you to pass either the current date (and time) or one you specify to the next action. There is another action called ‘Adjust Date’ which takes a date/time input and allows you perform a calculation against it. In this case, I will select the current date in ‘Date’ and add 30 minutes to it using ‘Adjust Date’. I now have a date/time value to pass along to ‘Set Do Not Disturb’ as the time until which I would like Do Not Disturb active.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2018/nap-time/shortcuts-date-math.png" style="max-width: 375px" alt="Do Not Disturb settings screenshot" /></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="timer">Timer</h3>

<p>Now I need to set a timer.</p>

<p>Frustratingly, Shortcuts does not have any built-in actions for the Clock app. If I hadn’t listened to a few podcasts over the last couple of months of people using Shortcuts in beta, I would have been stumped.</p>

<p>The way to get timer actions into a shortcut is to use Siri Suggestions. So activate Siri and say “Set a timer for 30 minutes.” Let it run or not. Now go back to the Shortcuts app and select Siri Suggestions in the action list and Siri will suggest to you your recent action you took with the Clock app—in this case “Start a timer for 30 minutes.”</p>

<p>This action can go as the last link your chain. You can choose whether you want to be left in the Clock app with the timer running or not when the shortcut terminates.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2018/nap-time/shortcuts-timer.png" style="max-width: 375px" alt="Timer shortcut screenshot" /></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="configuration">Configuration</h3>

<p>There’s a settings panel for your shortcut if you tap the toggle switch icon in the top right of the screen. There you can give your shortcut a name and icon. You can also record a Siri trigger phrase so that the new shortcut can be invoked by saying “Run ‘Nap Time’” to Siri where ‘Nap Time’ is whatever trigger phrase you’ve chosen.</p>

<p><img src="/images/2018/nap-time/shortcuts-settings.png" style="max-width: 375px" alt="Shortcut settings screenshot" /></p>

<hr />

<h3 id="additions">Additions</h3>

<p>I could also have this play a playlist in Music as well, but what I would really want is for the new <a href="http://www.numerogroup.com/products/environments">Environments</a> app of Irv Teibel field recordings from the Numero Group to start up. Unfortunately it doesn’t appear to have the necessary hooks to work with Shortcuts, so I will have to start it up manually if I want to. I can at least launch the app as the last step in my workflow if I want to.</p>

<hr />

<p>You can <a href="/downloads/nap-time.shortcut">download the shortcut</a> if you would like a head start messing with this stuff. It’s fun.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 14:29:40 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/18/nap-time.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/18/nap-time.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Coupland on omniscience fatigue</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>I’ve noticed that, as we ramp up on our game-building skills and generalized knowledge about Ronald [MacDonald], we’re googling every ten seconds. The problem is, after a week of intense googling, we’ve started to burn out on knowing the answer to everything. God must feel that way all the time. I think people in the year 2020 are going to be nostalgic for the sensation of feeling clueless.</p>

  <p>– <cite>From Douglas Coupland’s 2006 novel <i>JPod</i></cite></p>
</blockquote>

<p>I read this when it came out, but recently picked it up off the bookshelf where it was left by friends in the house we’re living in in Gent.</p>

<p>I was struck both by the prescience of this insight and how Coupland actually is a bit behind the curve. I feel like the nostalgia for unanswered questions (or a fatigue of relative omniscience?) has already been with us for a few years.</p>

<p>Now, still two years in advance of 2020, knowledge and fact are so cheap our problem is with how many of us have decided they are worthless—a far less blissful ignorance.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2018 21:23:01 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/17/googling.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/17/googling.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Driftless Recordings</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>Every once in a while I’ll stumble on a collection of things that articulates a sensibility (my sensibility?) so comprehensively and surprisingly that I have to know more.</p>

<p>I recently got a notice that <a href="https://c418.org/">C418</a>–the German producer of the soundtrack for the videogame Minecraft—was releasing a new album. I own the <a href="https://c418.bandcamp.com/album/minecraft-volume-alpha">Minecraft soundtrack on vinyl</a> because I like the music, but also because I got a kick out of the <a href="https://tinaja.computer/2016/04/26/videogames-on-vinyl.html">trend</a> for painstakingly packaged physical releases of these born-digital compositions that got under way a few years ago. I would have let this one pass me by because I just bought several new records a few days ago, but I saw the <a href="https://twitter.com/ghostramp">@ghostramp</a> account post about it on Twitter mentioning a label I’d never heard of, so I followed up.</p>

<p>It’s on a label I’d never heard of: <a href="http://www.driftlessrecordings.com/">Driftless Recordings</a>.<sup id="fnref:name"><a href="#fn:name" class="footnote">1</a></sup> I was expecting more videogame music. There is none. I scrolled down the list of records not recognizing anything, and then saw that they had a <a href="https://www.npr.org/sections/allsongs/2017/03/29/521813547/hayden-pedigos-greetings-from-amarillo-is-a-desert-swept-waltz-in-12-strings">Hayden Pedigo</a> record as an early release. And an ambient compilation produced for Moogfest. Videogame music composers and 12-string guitar instrumentals on the same label? I am intrigued.</p>

<p>And then there is this righteous album artwork by <a href="http://www.brianblomerth.com/">Brian Blomerth</a>:</p>

<p><img src="/images/2018/DFS037_COVER_WEB.JPG" alt="North Americans cover" /></p>

<p>for a band called North Americans I have also never heard of.<sup id="fnref:mcdermott"><a href="#fn:mcdermott" class="footnote">2</a></sup> So I watch the video I had initially scrolled past.</p>

<div class="youtube-video">
    <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aF1prRX96J8?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; encrypted-media" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>
</div>

<p>And it is so great. More guitar instrumentals. More ambience. Whistling. Julianna Barwick plays synth elsewhere on the record according to the review in <a href="https://www.tinymixtapes.com/news/ambient-guitar-outfit-north-americans-announce-upcoming-lp-driftless-recordings">Tiny Mix Tapes</a>. It’s a cascade of more things I’m into that I previously didn’t know.</p>

<p>I get bummed out about algorithmic smoothing of taste and aesthetics, particularly online. I get bummed out about the way that online forms box in the expression of identity by forcing the self to be shared in a way that fits the data expectations of a particular platform or piece of software. And then, every once in a while, the Internet still throws up something that doesn’t make much sense as anything other than itself. This collection of stuff was that for me yesterday, and it was a blast.</p>

<p>When you buy stuff on their store, you can throw in a mystery record for another $5. I did. Can it be possible I won’t be into it?</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:name">
      <p>It’s a good name. <a href="#fnref:name" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:mcdermott">
      <p>Turns out it’s not a band, but the recording name of Patrick McDermott, one of the label co-founders. <a href="#fnref:mcdermott" class="reversefootnote">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/09/driftless-recordings.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/09/driftless-recordings.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Girl Detectives, Soccer, and VHS Tapes</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0465094481/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Laurent Dubois. <i>The Language of the Game: How to Understand Soccer</i>. New York: Basic Books, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I read this while the World Cup was on. I know Laurent Dubois from my graduate work reading the Atlantic World historiography, but since then he has become one of my favorite writers on sports as well. This book is arranged in chapters using different participants in the game—players by position, managers, referees, fans—to anchor thematic observations on politics, gender, race, and culture in soccer.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1029830233">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0465094481/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062430483/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jason Fagone. <i>The Woman Who Smashed Codes: A True Story of Love, Spies, and the Unlikely Heroine Who Outwitted America’s Enemies</i>. New York: Dey Street Books, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I was completely unaware of the specifics of the bureaucratic apparatus (and really lack thereof) for code breaking during World War II, but that is hardly the only interesting aspect of this. Not only are there many other axes of interest for history of science and technology in the different communities of research and scholarship that Elizebeth Friedman moved through, but I appreciate Fagone’s enthusiastic championing of his subject and her largely unheralded work.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1005678196">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062430483/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0785196579/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Tom King, Gabriel Hernandez, Jordie Bellaire, and Clayton Cowles. <i>The Vision, Vol. 1: Little Worse than a Man</i>. New York: Marvel, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Max Temkin strongly recommended this on the <a href="http://dobyfriday.com">Do By Friday</a> podcast. I think there may be a little bit of context I’m missing from not being familiar with the larger story of Vision, but nonetheless I thought it was a pretty interesting exploration of what makes community (through both exclusion and inclusion) and how identities are constructed.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/995294999">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0785196579/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250159997/ref=nosim/latin031-20">John Darnielle. <i>Universal Harvester: A Novel</i>. New York: Picador, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p><em>Universal Harvester</em> builds a strong sense of place in late 90s Iowa in which its quiet, suspenseful almost-horror sits neatly next to people living with loss and grief. Darnielle’s experience building characters in the small spaces of songs shows itself in his knack for finding the small exemplary. This writing felt patient and confident; I really enjoyed being in and moving slowly through this world.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/981966720">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1250159997/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1400067219/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Kurt Andersen. <i>Fantasyland: How America Went Haywire</i>. New York: Random House, 2018.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Kurt Andersen traces the development of magical thinking and individualistic ‘truth’ in American culture from early English settlement to the present day. He does a good job summarizing the early modern cultural history. It’s a survey, and I’m not the imagined audience for it, but it was nice to see this perspective on early American Protestant religion in a work of popular nonfiction. Andersen’s clear interest is in the second half of the twentieth century when he argues that the American predeliction for personal truth, facilitated by the counterculture and postmodernism, allow for an explosion of non-reality-based worldviews across the political and cultural spectrum. The obvious endpoint is the era of the Trump presidency. In tying this moment to a long history fusing individualistic and supernatural worldviews into a uniquely American epistemology, Andersen helpfully challenges the idea that this Trumpist moment is some kind of catastrophic rupture rather than inherently American.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1027554418">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1400067219/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01L2WGIQY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Hope Larson and Brittney Williams. <i>Goldie Vance, vol. 1</i>. Los Angeles: BOOM! Box, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I picked this out at the comic book store with Mees having seen it mentioned before as a good book for kids. It’s a nice Nancy Drew- or Harriet the Spy-like girl-detective story about a precocious teenager who takes it upon herself to act as house detective at South Florida hotel where her father works in a early 1960s setting. The primary young characters are people of color and the teen romance is not exclusively heterosexual. The artwork is colorful and fun, and the action is mostly non-violent. It was a worthwhile read for my own enjoyment, but it’s also definitely a great option for non-superhero comics for kids.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1045029093">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01L2WGIQY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0345807154/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jo Nesbø. <i>Cockroaches: The Second Inspector Harry Hole Novel</i>. London: Harvill Secker, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>When I started reading the Harry Hole series, the installment available in English was <em>The Redbreast</em>, which is actually the third book in the series. Almost ten years later, it’s interesting to return to this earlier entry. It’s a page-turner the way they all are. Having spent a short time in Bangkok staying with Northern European ex-pat friends, it was interesting to see Nesbø’s frame for conflicts between Thai and ex-pat culture, particularly as he seems to experience it differently as a Northern European than I do as an American.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/875496861">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0345807154/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062409166/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Neal Stephenson and Nicole Galland. <i>The Rise and Fall of D.O.D.O.: A Novel</i>. New York: William Morrow, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This was lighter reading than some Stephenson fare—more like <em>Zodiac</em> than <em>Sevenes</em>—and ends up as a sort of time-traveling heist novel that mashes up Big Science and the occult, the military and academia. The narrative is presented in letters, networked groupware messaging platforms, and journals. On both these counts it’s reminiscent of other things I’ve read recently, but far more successful. I’m not familiar with Nicole Galland, but I’m sort of curious to read her historical fiction now, and I’m glad to see indications that this is the first installment in a series.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/959038737">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062409166/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 10:35:40 +0200</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/04/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2018/09/04/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>