<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>La Tinaja</title>
<description>My name is Brian Jones. These are my notes on topics including books, publishing, tech, and history.</description>
<link>http://tinaja.computer</link>
<atom:link href="http://tinaja.computer/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Dave Winer on Misunderstanding and Design</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>Sometimes when people misunderstand a product or feature they give you ideas for how it might work or for another product or feature. Creativity sometimes comes just from not knowing something. Another reason it’s important to listen, you never know how new ideas will arrive.</p>

  <p>– <cite><a href="http://scripting.com/2017/09/08.html#a112822">Dave Winer</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2017 15:13:01 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/14/winer-on-misunderstanding.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/14/winer-on-misunderstanding.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Superheroes, Pilates, and Autotune</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00DG292XK/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Sean Howe. <i>Marvel Comics: The Untold Story</i>. New York: Harper Perennial, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I’ve always been interested in having a greater understanding of the long trajectory of both the history of the Marvel story universe and of Marvel as a business, having followed comic books for only about a year as a teenager but enjoyed being generally aware of the current set of ”important” books in recent years. This chronicle is incredibly detailed which made it a little slow going when I didn’t have any outside familiarity with the material, but it was well done and interesting. I’m glad to have read it and enjoyed it, even when I moved slowly through some eras.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/963603235">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00DG292XK/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01N43SQER/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Harri Angell. <i>Pilates for Runners</i>. London: Bloomsbury Sport, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>There’s just enough theory here to make the reading worthwhile, but the main focus of the book is clear descriptions of mat Pilates exercises and sample routines targeted at runners’ strength and flexibility needs.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/957021150">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01N43SQER/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B019CBM636/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jayce Clayton. <i>Uproot: Travels in Twenty-First-Century Music and Global Digital Culture</i>. New York: Farrar Straus & Giroux, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p><em>Uproot</em> is an incredibly compelling blend of artist memoir, cultural criticism, and music and travel writing that does an amazing job of addressing the influence of digital media formats, recording and production tools, broadcasting and performance technologies, and more on listening, performance, and composition in music today. I share Clayton’s affinity for some of the regional styles he explores and am completely unaware of others, so I look forward to following through on those.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/953157396">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B019CBM636/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B010ZXKDBC/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Andie Mitchell. <i>Eating in the Middle: A Mostly Wholesome Cookbook</i>. New York: Clarkson Potter, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The organizing principle of this book is to find ways to adjust cooking techniques and substitute ingredients in comfort foods to make them a bit more healthful while still being satisfying. Many of the recipes themselves are good, but the biggest help for me was as an exercise in finding ways to make adjustments to lower calories in other recipes.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/991055834">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B010ZXKDBC/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B002VUFKDY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Daniel Suarez. <i>Freedom</i>. New York: Signet, 2010.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I enjoy this series, but continue to wish there was more focus on world building and less on action. I was struck reading this by how it prefigures some of the ideas Cory Doctorow explored in <a href="http://tinaja.computer/2017/05/24/recent-reading.html"><em>Walkaway</em></a> although without the same degree of rigorous analysis. It makes for more of a page-turner, but also it is fundamentally a less ambitious work.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/617551227">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B002VUFKDY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 15:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/11/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/09/11/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Mac Apps I Use</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>This week I kept a running list of the applications I used on my Mac at least once.</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="https://flyingmeat.com/acorn/">Acorn 6</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://alfredapp.com">Alfred 3</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://atom.io">Atom</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://bear-writer.com">Bear</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.busymac.com/busycal/">BusyCal</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.google.com/chrome/browser/desktop/index.html">Chrome</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.devontechnologies.com/products/devonthink/devonthink-pro-office.html">DEVONthink Pro Office</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://products.office.com/en-US/excel">Excel</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://flexibits.com/fantastical">Fantastical 2</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox">Firefox</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://gitkraken.com">GitKraken</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://gitup.co">GitUp</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://hyper.is">Hyper</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.apple.com/itunes/download/">iTunes</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.kaleidoscopeapp.com">Kaleidoscope</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/kindle-dbs/fd/kcp">Kindle</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://freron.com">MailMate</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.mamp.info/en/mamp-pro/">MAMP Pro</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://manytricks.com/moom/">Moom</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://noteplan.co">NotePlan</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus">OmniFocus 2</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.omnigroup.com/omnioutliner">OmniOutliner 5</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1548768604/twitterrific-for-mac-project-phoenix">Phoenix</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://matthewpalmer.net/rocket/">Rocket</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.apple.com/safari/">Safari</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://slack.com">Slack</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://www.acqualia.com/soulver/">Soulver</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://bananafishsoftware.com/products/spillo/">Spillo</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://panic.com/transmit/">Transmit 5</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://typora.io">Typora</a></li>
  <li><a href="http://tableflipapp.com">TableFlip</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://eternalstorms.at/yoink/Yoink_-_Simplify_and_Improve_Drag_and_Drop_on_your_Mac/Yoink_-_Simplify_drag_and_drop_on_your_Mac.html">Yoink</a></li>
</ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/08/31/mac-apps.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/08/31/mac-apps.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Bitcoin, Spider Jerusalem, and API Design</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01D8KFX9Q/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Nathaniel Popper. <i>Digital Gold: Bitcoin and the Inside Story of the Misfits and Millionaires Trying to Reinvent Money</i>. New York: Harper, 2015.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Listened to this as an audiobook over an incredibly long time in small, disjointed pieces, so I am not certain that I have the most fair impression of it. Some interesting detail here and there on early Bitcoin ventures, but a lot on the Silk Road felt like it had been done elsewhere and in general it felt like there was a lack of much analytical value. Helpful as a descriptive timeline for readers looking for that detail, but my impression was that wasn’t much of a point of view here.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/953442959">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01D8KFX9Q/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00HO12CRW/ref=nosim/latin031-20">J. Michael Orenduff. <i>The Pot Thief Who Studied Einstein</i>. The Pot Thief Mysteries, no. 3. New York: Open Road, 2011.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The third installment in this light, easy-reading cozy mystery series. More of the same, really, but I continue to enjoy the Albuquerque setting while reading from Berlin.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/889943664">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00HO12CRW/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0692232699/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Phil Sturgeon. <i>Build APIs You Won’t Hate: Everyone and Their Dog Wants an API, So You Should Probably Learn How to Build Them</i>. Self-published, 2015.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The earlier chapters of this book focus more on design and theory and were very helpful for someone coming to API design without a lot of confidence that they even know the right questions to ask. Just having read these three or four early chapters would have been sufficient for me to be more comfortable venturing off on my own. The demonstration code in the more practically-oriented ermainder of the book is in PHP and assumes some of the author’s own libraries for which there are not necessarily ready equivalents in other languages, but it is nonetheless clearly written enough that it should be helpful demonstration for any reader.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/990938288">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0692232699/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B009POHIE8/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Warren Ellis. <i>Transmetropolitan, Vol. 1: Back on the Street</i>. New York: DC Comics, 2009.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I have read so much other Warren Ellis and have never read his most famous series. This first volume was a blast and coincidentally fell nicely in line with my accidental streak of reading late 80s and 90s stuff counter culture and hacker culture stuff recently. Interesting unexpected resonances with today’s media and political climate two decades later.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/772553475">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B009POHIE8/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B0087ORPFO/ref=nosim/latin031-20">John Sandford. <i>The Empress File</i>. New York: Berkley Books, 1991.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The second installment in a late 80s and early 90s thriller series about a computer penetration specialist and painter, this time running a con on a political cabal in a small Southern city. More tightly written than the <a href="/2017/07/14/recent-reading.html">first one</a>, but there was less emphasis on the computer exploits that provided some of the nostalgic interest of the first one.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/229231956">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B0087ORPFO/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 14:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/07/26/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/07/26/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Crowdsourcing, Pots, and GIS</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01M1NPEUM/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Christine Koh and Asha Dornfest. <i>Minimalist Parenting: Enjoy Modern Family Life More by Doing Less</i>. Brookline, MA: Bibliomotion, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Relatively cruft-free as far as self-help/parenting books go, provides both some useful framing for approaching decisions around just how much one wants to do to run a household and discrete practical ‘tips and tricks’ for pursuing it. The “minimalist” framing frequently feels shoehorned into sections to maintain a consistent language to match the marketing-friendly title, but not to the extent of distracting from the book’s usefulness.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/823472877">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01M1NPEUM/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00HO12CTK/ref=nosim/latin031-20">J. Michael Orenduff. <i>The Pot Thief Who Studied Pythagoras</i>. The Pot Thief Mysteries, no. 1. New York: Open Road, 2009.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is the first installment in a series of <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cozy_mystery">cozy mysteries</a> about a ceramics shop owner in Albuquerque who stumbles through a series of mix-ups involving murder and contraband artifacts. The author has a political hobby horse with regards to cultural heritage policy that results in some unpleasant monologues from the protagonist from time to time, but the Albuquerque setting and light mood make it enjoyable reading. There are some first book jitters here in the writing and plotting that fortunately shake out in the second one.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/889943723">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00HO12CTK/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00HO12CSQ/ref=nosim/latin031-20">J. Michael Orenduff. <i>The Pot Thief Who Studied Ptolemy</i>. The Pot Thief Mysteries, no. 2. New York: Open Road, 2010.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The second installment in this cozy mystery series set in Albuquerque cleans up some of the first book rough edges from <em>The Pot Thief Who Studied Pythagoras</em>. This one develops the appealing Albuquerque setting a bit more and presents some humorous caricature of academia.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/889943657">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00HO12CSQ/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/9400750080/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Alexander von Lünen and Charles Travis, eds. <i>History and GIS: Epistemologies, Considerations and Reflections</i>. Dordrecht: Springer Netherlands, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The organizing principle of this collection of interviews and essays is to encourage historians to consider the epistemological consequences of GIS as tool of inquiry and an exploratory methodology, rather than as a piece of the production process useful only for creating static maps as ‘end products’. The Gunnar Olsson and David Staley interviews and von Lünen’s concluding essay were of particular interest in helping to consider the boundaries of what geographical inquiry (and GIS in particular) can do to expand the questions available to historians.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/829432729">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/9400750080/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00CHQRJ3G/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Daren C. Brabham. <i>Crowdsourcing</i>. The MIT Press Essential Knowledge Series. Cambridge, MA: The MIT Press, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This short book presents a synthesis of academic research on crowdsourcing across a variety of academic disciplines including computer science, business, and the social sciences. It provides a useful working definition of what constitutes ‘crowdsourcing’ (and what it is not) and runs through both positive indications for its future as a tool in a variety of fields and ethical and political problems it presents that must be addressed. A quick read and useful for shaping design considerations for possible online projects that would include collaborative peer contributions (though, per the reading, not necessarily ‘crowdsourcing’).</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/813540906">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00CHQRJ3G/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2017 05:34:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/07/14/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/07/14/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Extracting Substrings from URLs with Alfred Workflows</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I frequently find myself needing to extract a predictable piece of data from a URL, like a product id, for pasting into a file or database as metadata that might be used to contact an API or construct cleaned-up URLs in the future. The predictable formatting of the part of the URL that I care about makes this the kind of task that perfectly lends itself to simple automation, saving me the small friction of manually editing these URLs in place.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.alfredapp.com/workflows/">Alfred workflows</a> are a quick way to run this category of automation. Because the data is in a URL, I’m typically copying the URL from my web browser to the clipboard and pasting it into a text editor or field. With an Alfred workflow, I can run a script on the text from the clipboard and put my desired result back on the clipboard, cleaned up and ready to paste wherever I’d like.</p>

<p>I have several workflows that fit this general use case, and my interaction with all of them follows the following pattern:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Me:</strong> Copy my starting text to the clipboard</li>
  <li><strong>Me:</strong> Invoke the workflow with an Alfred keyword
    <ul>
      <li><strong>Alfred:</strong> Grab the contents of the clipboard</li>
      <li><strong>Alfred:</strong> Run a short Python script on that data</li>
      <li><strong>Alfred:</strong> Copy the result of the script back to the clipboard</li>
      <li><em>(optionally)</em> <strong>Alfred:</strong> Paste the result of the script to the currently active window</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li><strong>Me:</strong> Paste the text now in the clipboard where I want it if I haven’t already allowed Alfred to do it for me</li>
</ul>

<p>To take a specific example, we can walk through building a workflow to extract the OCLC number for an edition of a book from a <a href="http://worldcat.org">Worldcat.org</a> URL.</p>

<hr />

<p>A typical URL for a book on Worldcat.org reached through their onsite search might look like the following:</p>

<p><code class="highlighter-rouge">http://www.worldcat.org/title/history-and-gis-epistemologies-considerations-and-reflections/oclc/910980341&amp;referer=brief_results</code></p>

<p>The only part I care about are the numerals between <code class="highlighter-rouge">/oclc/</code> and the <code class="highlighter-rouge">&amp;</code> (in this case, <code class="highlighter-rouge">910980341</code>). With that unique identifier I can construct my own tidier Worldcat.org URLs later or use their API in a script.</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="/images/2017/OCLC-workflow-overview.jpg" alt="Complete Alfred Workflow Screenshot" /></p>

<p>The screenshot above shows the final layout of the workflow. Assuming we have the URL on the clipboard, the workflow performs the following actions:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Launch when invoked with the keyword <code class="highlighter-rouge">oclc</code> from Alfred</li>
  <li>Grab the clipboard contents with a bash script</li>
  <li>Take those contents and match them against a simple regular expression (in this case in a Python script)</li>
  <li>Copy to the clipboard and paste in the front most app</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="1-launch">1. Launch</h3>

<p><img src="/images/2017/OCLC-1-launch.jpg" alt="Launch Settings" /></p>

<p>In the Alfred workflow editor, create a new ‘Input’ of the ‘Keyword’ type, select the keyword you would like to use to invoke your workflow, and give it a descriptive title.</p>

<h3 id="2-grab-clipboard">2. Grab Clipboard</h3>

<p>Link your ‘Keyword’ input to a new ’Action’ of type ’Run Script’. You can leave all of the sets for this script alone; the default language choice, <code class="highlighter-rouge">/bin/bash</code>, is what we want in this case. Our script will be a single bash command to grab the contents of the clipboard.</p>

<div class="language-bash highlighter-rouge"><pre class="highlight"><code>pbpaste
</code></pre>
</div>

<h3 id="3-find-oclc">3. Find OCLC</h3>

<p>Link your <code class="highlighter-rouge">/bin/bash</code> ‘Run Script’ action to a new ’Action’ of type ’Run Script’. This time we will want to change our settings for the Language to <code class="highlighter-rouge">/usr/bin/python</code>. (All we’re doing is matching a regular expression which would be possible using any of the language options. I just like Python.)</p>

<p>The script is simple. We take the input from our bash script that grabbed the clipboard contents and we match it against a regular expression that essentially says “Give me the run of numerals that follow the string <code class="highlighter-rouge">/oclc/</code> in the provided text.” Finally, we write our result to standard output which is how our next Alfred action will receive it.</p>

<div class="language-python highlighter-rouge"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="kn">import</span> <span class="nn">re</span>
<span class="kn">import</span> <span class="nn">sys</span>

<span class="n">url</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="s">"{query}"</span>

<span class="n">matchObj</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="n">re</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">search</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s">r'/oclc/([0-9]*)'</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="n">url</span><span class="p">)</span>

<span class="n">sys</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">stdout</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">write</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">matchObj</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">group</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">))</span>
</code></pre>
</div>

<p>A couple of things to note:</p>

<ol>
  <li><code class="highlighter-rouge"><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">query</span><span class="p">}</span></code> is a placeholder Alfred looks for in our script in order to insert whatever string of data is coming from the previous action in our workflow. It is not a standard piece of Python syntax.</li>
  <li>A ‘regular expression’ is a string of characters that defines a pattern of text. In the case of the above script, it is the part that reads <code class="highlighter-rouge">/oclc/([0-9]*)</code>, but they can be far more complex. For a good introduction to using regular expressions, you can look at the Google lesson on <a href="https://developers.google.com/edu/python/regular-expressions">Python Regular Expressions</a>.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="4-output">4. Output</h3>

<p><img src="/images/2017/OCLC-4-output.jpg" alt="Output Settings" /></p>

<p>Finally, we just want to link a new ‘Output’ of type ‘Copy to Clipboard’ and use the default content which is just to pass through the input from our Python script. Depending on the context, we could do additional formatting here by editing the text around <code class="highlighter-rouge"><span class="p">{</span><span class="err">query</span><span class="p">}</span></code>.</p>

<p>In this case, I have also checked the box to ‘Automatically paste to front most app’ because that matches my needs the vast majority of the time I’m using this particular workflow, but in some cases it may be preferable to leave the result on the clipboard without automatically pasting.</p>

<hr />

<p>That’s it. This approach can be repeated for any number of small extraction tasks—to take ASIN numbers from Amazon.com product links in order to construct affiliate links, for example.</p>

<p>Any single instance of this task would be trivial to perform manually, but Alfred’s ability to combine interaction with the clipboard and access to a scripting language with nice regular expression support triggered through a quick-launch command kills the tedious friction of repeat manual editing and becomes second nature.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 05:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/07/03/URL-substring-alfred-workflows.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/07/03/URL-substring-alfred-workflows.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Zodiacs, Hackers, and Geography</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B004IATCES/ref=nosim/latin031-20">John Sandford. <i>The Fool’s Run</i>. New York: Berkley Books, 1989.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>A late 80s techno-thriller with a painter-hacker protagonist who has to explain personal computing fundamentals to his partners on a corporate espionage gig. A decent page-turner that is the first in a series on which I plan to follow through.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/988526544">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B004IATCES/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0674066480/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Sean Roberts. <i>Printing a Mediterranean World: Florence, Constantinople, and the Renaissance of Geography</i>. Cambridge, MA: Harvard University Press, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Roberts uses the gift of a printed edition of a late fifteenth-century Florentine geography to two Ottoman rulers as a jumping off point to explore the ‘rediscovery’ of geography and the materiality of knowledge and exchange in the late medieval and early modern Mediterranean world. He expands on the existing trend in complicating the supposedly transformative and modernizing effects taof the reintroduction of Ptolemy’s <em>Geography</em> into European intellectual life, but his primary contribution is in exploring the specific material characteristics of the book in question to identify the local peculiarities of commerce, geopolitics, and religion that shaped a Mediterranean world traditionally presumed to be aggressively transnational and multicultural.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/900039945">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0674066480/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B008UX8SNU/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Neal Stephenson. <i>Zodiac</i>. New York: Bantam Books, 1988.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p><em>Zodiac</em> was only Stephenson’s second novel, and it is interesting to read something with his voice in which some of his more idiosyncratic qualities (long technical digressions, large-scale world-building at the expense of plotting, etc.) have yet to develop. It’s a relatively short and tight thriller about corporate corruption and ecopolitics with a late 80s Generation-X-y tone that is evocative of the era.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/678839423">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B008UX8SNU/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 04:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/07/01/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/07/01/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Sean Roberts on the Materiality of Books</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>What we can learn about books and their relationship to the ideas they supposedly contain has everything to do with the ways in which people interacted with them and the ways in which books conditioned those interactions. In short, another way of asking what we can learn from books might be to ask <em>how</em> we learn from books. At a moment when so many of us are moving ever more rapidly away from “hard copies” and embracing eBooks of all varieties, it is worth remembering that the material properties of books long set important conditions for their reading. Indeed, even the electronic simulacra to which we now find ourselves accustomed imitate physical acts like turning pages, inserting ribbons, and dog-earing corners. Virtual book collections take on the appearance of wooden shelves and follow organizational schemes derived from physical libraries. All such mimicry, of course, comes at great expense both to processing resources and programming hours. Yet it is deemed indispensable because reading remains a stubbornly material act.</p>

  <p>– <cite>Sean Roberts, <a href="http://www.worldcat.org/title/printing-a-mediterranean-world-florence-constantinople-and-the-renaissance-of-geography/oclc/900039945">Printing a Mediterranean World: Florence, Constantinople, and the Renaissance of Geography</a>, p. 175.</cite></p>
</blockquote>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Mon, 26 Jun 2017 16:13:01 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/06/26/roberts-on-materiality-of-books.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/06/26/roberts-on-materiality-of-books.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Mario, Garbage, and Computational Abundance</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01H2KDZ7A/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Alyse Knorr. <i>Super Mario Bros. 3</i>. Los Angeles, CA: Boss Fight Books, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is another entry in the Boss Fight Books series that is as much personal memoir as exploration of the game itself. Knorr interrogates gamer nostalgia through a thorough analysis of the game mechanics and level design of Super Mario Bros. 3 in the context of the widely held consensus that is a great, if not the greatest, platform game ever made. Along the way, her own nostalgia for childhood family interactions around the game adds an additional layer to the contingent nature of media experience.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/951476372">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01H2KDZ7A/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B011JAV030/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Sarah Jeong. <i>The Internet of Garbage</i>. New York: Forbes Media, 2015.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Jeong has done a great job making the case both for the importance of community moderation online and in explaining how that work is much more nuanced than blocking, deleting, and banning.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B011JAV030/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00D97HPQI/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Erik Brynjolfsson and Andrew McAfee. <i>The Second Machine Age: Work, Progress, and Prosperity in a Time of Brilliant Technologies</i>. New York: W.W. Norton & Company, 2014.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>In this readable account, Brynjolfsson and McAfee outline some of the tensions between conventional economic wisdom and new realities of labor and markets in an age of computational abundance. While not discounting the looming hardships for many workers, they are generally sanguine about the continued need for human labor provided that training is geared to maximizing those human strengths for which machines can serve only as complements, rather than substitutes. As with so many business books, the historical foundations of some of their arguments make their shallow approach to historiography a bit disappointing. The work’s strength comes from the pair’s clear explication of policy prescriptions from their analysis.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/960056027">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00D97HPQI/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1118987241/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Brad Williams, David Damstra, and Hal Stern. <i>Professional WordPress: Design and Development</i>. Indianapolis, IN: Wrox, 2015.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Having never done more than hacked together limited rough-and-ready custom one-off changes to WordPress themes, I felt like I need a good A-Z overview of the world of WordPress development as a foundation for a project I’m working on. Spending a week or so with this book following a single path orchestrated by a constant and consistent author saved me a lot of the time and confusion I’ve been wasting on abortive strolls through developer blogs and howtos over the last few months.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/913971983">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1118987241/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 09:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/06/21/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/06/21/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Rebecca Solnit on Privilege and Obliviousness</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>This is why I always pair privilege with obliviousness; obliviousness is privilege’s form of deprivation. When you don’t hear others, you don’t imagine them, they become unreal, and you are left in the wasteland of a world with only yourself in it, and that surely makes you starving, though you know not for what, if you have ceased to imagine others exist in any true deep way that matters. This is about a need for which we hardly have language or at least not a familiar conversation.</p>

  <p>– <cite>Rebecca Solnit, <a href="http://lithub.com/rebecca-solnit-the-loneliness-of-donald-trump/">The Loneliness of Donald Trump</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 01:23:01 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://tinaja.computer/2017/05/31/solnit-on-privilege.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://tinaja.computer/2017/05/31/solnit-on-privilege.html</guid>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>