<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<channel>
<title>La Tinaja</title>
<description>My name is Brian Jones. These are my notes on topics including books, publishing, tech, and history.</description>
<link>http://localhost:4000</link>
<atom:link href="http://tinaja.computer/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

<item>
<title>Forced HTTPS in Chrome on Local .dev Domains</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I used to use .dev as a domain extension for doing local development using <a href="http://mamp.info">MAMP Pro</a>, but 
I have had to switch to using .local instead because Safari and Chrome both now force any 
domain ending in .dev to load over HTTPS which I’m not running for my local development 
environments.</p>

<p>Google made this decision (and Apple is following their lead) because Google bought the 
rights to provide .dev as a publicly available TLD and will be putting them on sale in 
May of this year. For now the browser-side enforcement of the HTTPS-only policy is 
inconvenient, but it means making a change that I would need to make regardless to avoid 
potential collisions in the future.</p>

<p>This is a new enough situation that I still have old projects for which I haven’t changed the 
settings. When I try to load them, I get the message that the server is unavailable even though 
I’m looking at MAMP Pro chugging away right in front of me. This happens sufficiently infrequently 
that it still takes me about five or ten minutes of confusion to remember the cause and 
change over to a .local domain.</p>

<p>As usual, the hope is that writing up a short note will mean I remember what’s going on 
next time.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 06:28:01 -0500</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/10/dot-dev.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/02/10/dot-dev.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: Cyber War, Berlin, and Teenage Sleuths</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00KAJX6XY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Dick Lochte. <i>Sleeping Dog</i>. Leawood, KS: Brash Books, 2014 [1985].</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The first in a series of two mysteries based on the conflicting unreliable narrator pair of a middle-aged detective and a precocious teenage girl. It was fun and the texture of its 1980’s California setting was enjoyable. I will read the next one.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/1011684362">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00KAJX6XY/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1476763267/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Fred M. Kaplan. <i>Dark Territory: The Secret History of Cyber War</i>. New York: Simon & Schuster, 2016.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Kaplan is a journalist who focuses on national security and this history of cyberwar focuses much more on the security implications of computer surveillance, intrusion, and sabotage than it does on the mechanics of it. It’s a useful history from that perspective. I listened to it as an audiobook and did so over too long a time, so this may be on me, but I have the impression that the construction of this story from anecdotal episodes meant that there was not a lot of thematic development. I am glad to have read it, but also want more.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/987329985">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1476763267/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0684832674/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Katie Hafner and Matthew Lyon. <i>Where Wizards Stay Up Late: The Origins of the Internet</i>. New York: Simon & Schuster, 1996.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I appreciate this genre of computing histories in which the author(s) have a keen sense of the technical detail they are covering and recreate historical technical decisions at a relatively detailed granularity. It is not so specific as <a href="http://tinaja.computer/2017/04/07/disrupted-and-blitzed.html"><em>The Cuckoo’s Egg</em></a>, but it does remind me of that in this regard. The authors tell the story of the creation of the ARPANET in great detail and signal towards its evolution into the Internet. As I get more interested in reading platform studies, I wish there were a bit more critical analysis of the historical sources, but the work is also twenty years old and written for a trade press, so this is not a surprising omission.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/937944832">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0684832674/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00LOV2DOA/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Antony Johnston and Sam Hart. <i>The Coldest City: A Graph Novel<i>. Portland: Oni Press, 2012.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>An atmospheric spy story set in 1989 Berlin with defections, double crosses, and a stark visual style. The action unravels in a series of effective flashbacks from a debriefing of the protagonist. I’ve had this one lying around for forever and regret that it’s taken my desire to see the film adaptation <em>Atomic Blonde</em> to finally get into it. Will move on to the second book in the series immediately.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/914942904">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00LOV2DOA/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 16:54:49 -0500</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/30/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/30/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Media about Cities and Sea Levels</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>I read Paul Greenberg’s <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0143127438/ref=nosim/latin031-20">American Catch</a></em> <a href="http://tinaja.computer/2017/10/19/recent-reading.html">a few months ago</a> and while I enjoyed the whole thing, the most striking section to me was the material about oysters and New York City. The combination of food history, the interface between built and natural environments, and the marine pushed a lot of my buttons.</p>

<p>A recent 99% Invisible episode entitled “<a href="https://99percentinvisible.org/episode/oyster-tecture/">Oyster-tecture</a>” takes the same material as a jumping off point to dive more specifically into the oyster reef construction efforts of one of Greenberg’s subjects. The episode is great—as 99% Invisible so often is—but I hope it will also encourage more people to read Greenberg’s book.</p>

<p>In a similar vein, another of my favorite podcasts Track Changes has an <a href="https://trackchanges.postlight.com/talking-with-kim-stanley-robinson-about-his-global-warming-epic-new-york-2140-127a72460550">interview episode</a> with Kim Stanley Robinson on which he discusses his novel <em><a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01KT7YTO6/ref=nosim/latin031-20">New York 2140</a></em> (which I still need to read) and speculated on the consequences of rising sea levels for the built environment and urban geography of New York City.</p>


    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/21/oyster-tecture.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/21/oyster-tecture.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: CDs and Bottled Water</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1558328793/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Natalie Perry. <i>The Big Book of Paleo Slow Cooking: 200 Nourishing Recipes That Cook Carefree, for Everyday Dinners and Weekend Feasts</i>. Minneapolis, MN: Harvard Common Press, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I’m usually pretty skeptical of these tool-oriented cookbooks (e.g., the Dutch oven cookbook, the slow cooker cookbook, etc.) and the combination with paleo dieting is the second strike. However, it was on the recommendations table at the downtown library (which tends to have pretty good cookbook recommendations), so I picked it up. I’m not a paleo diet partisan, so I imagine I’ll ignore some of the more inconvenient substitutions made for more conventional ingredients, but I actually found a lot of the recipes here to be pretty promising. The spice profile on the ones I’ve tried has been on the mild side for my taste, but that’s an easy thing to address in future efforts.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/993767508">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1558328793/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00FEZ24QO/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Sherman Alexie. <i>Indian Killer</i>. New York: Grove Press, 1996.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Most of my fiction reading these days happens on a backlit Kindle Paperwhite on a couch in a toddler’s room after lights out. I found this really engrossing in that context. I love Sherman Alexie generally, and it was interesting to see him do something of a genre fiction exercise that, not surprisingly, transcends the typical limitations of the psychological thriller genre.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/612843404">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B00FEZ24QO/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01DOJCAGA/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Jason Aaron, Chris Bachalo, et al. <i>Doctor Strange, Vol. 1: The Way of the Weird</i>. New York: Marvel Worldwide, 2015.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I really like Jason Aaron’s <em>Scalped</em>, and I like the more mystical Marvel stuff like Doctor Strange and the Silver Surfer, so it’s no surprise that I enjoyed this. I was not familiar with Chris Bachalo, but his art actually turned out to be my favorite aspect of this book.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/917344058">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B01DOJCAGA/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B072C8R69H/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Steve Knopper. <i>Appetite for Self-Destruction: The Spectacular Crash of the Record Industry in the Digital Age</i>. New York: Free Press, 2009.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is an insightful history of the media trajectory of the music industry that created the anomalous peak of the CD era and the subsequent crash into the era of online distribution. Having come of age as a music consumer basically in lockstep with the rise of the CD format over the course of the 90s, I have been intellectually aware of the business distortions of the CD era, but my personal experience has made it difficult to relate to it. This book provided helpful perspective and historical distance in that regard. It was also fascinating to read this 2009 perspective in the year 2017 since streaming has taken off. In collecting bibliographic information for this title, I’ve seen that Knopper has had a chance to put out a new edition with a chapter on streaming this year. I’m curious to check it out, but also appreciate the first edition as a historical document.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/475718638">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B072C8R69H/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B004J4X32U/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Daniel J. Siegel and Tina Payne Bryson. <i>The Whole-Brain Child: 12 Proven Strategies to Nurture Your Child’s Developing Mind</i>. London: Robinson, 2012.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>The authors’ approach in this parenting manual is to package research in developmental psychology for a popular audience. The result, for me, is a much more interesting read than a lot of “tips and tricks”-style manuals in this space, but it is still a bit weighed down by some of the repetitive tropes of the genre. The concept of integrating and accommodating opposing mental modes (individual vs. social, emotional vs. intellectual, etc.) into a whole has been a compelling goal in approaching both positive and negative behavior.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/989110062">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B004J4X32U/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1559707739/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Ismail Kadare. <i>The Successor: A Novel</i>. Translated by Tedi Papavrami and David Bellos. New York: Arcade Publishing, 2013.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I found this novel about the mysterious death of a high-ranking  government official in Albania to be an interesting exploration of political fear, paranoia, and suspicion in the context of an authoritarian regime. The language is stark and detached in a way that creates a sensation of alienation that I imagine to be intentional, but the English translation comes by way of a French translation of the original Albanian. I’m never confident that I’m not simply over-reading a difficult translation in cases like these. Despite taking a while to get into the language, I eventually quite enjoyed it.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/816030082">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1559707739/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B008ON449S/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Mohsin Hamid. <i>How to Get Filthy Rich in Rising Asia</i>. New York: Riverhead Books, 2014.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>I enjoyed this quite a bit. It’s rather adventurous formally, presenting itself as a self-help book  with the goal of helping its reader achieve the titular goal of getting rich in the new Asia. The protagonist is the second person singular reader and the thematic chapters also trace the arc of that second person protagonist from birth through death in an unspecified, not-quite-Pakistan Asian country. The formal conceit may sound cute, but I found that it allowed Hamid to change frames from the intimately personal to the urban to the geopolitical freely. Having surrendered to the format quickly, I found it both touching and funny</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/878603083">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/B008ON449S/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 20:48:49 -0500</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/10/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/10/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Daniel Cook on ‘comfy games’</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>At a recent game designer retreat (Project Horseshoe) we had a working group trying to understand the psychology ‘comfy games’ like <em>Stardew Valley</em> or <em>Animal Crossing</em>. One thing we noticed is that many games focus on the bottom portion of Maslow’s Hierarchy of needs. They deal with survival, food, shelter and physical threats. Comfy games are instead comfortable spaces where you can work on some higher level human needs. You can dabble with self reflection, little social moments and maybe self expression. Games that treat players like higher order humans instead of twitchy, fear-based animals are a super cool thing!</p>

  <p>However, when a design introduces intense lower level needs, it can ruin the atmosphere that makes a comfy game work. <em>Pocket Camp</em> introduces time pressure and responsibility. If you don’t get that stupid sofa crafted before the animal leaves, you’ll miss a chance to progress along the checklist. Even when you do complete the task, it is entirely transactional. What would have been a mysterious quirky nuanced relationship in <em>Animal Crossing</em> is reduced to a meter incrementing so you can earn precious currency.  This is not an environment for self actualization. It is a place of rushed, time sensitive labor. Ugh.</p>

  <p>– <cite><a href="http://www.lostgarden.com/">Daniel Cook</a> on ‘comfy games’ at <a href="">Gamasutra</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 08:58:01 -0500</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/14/comfy-games.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/12/14/comfy-games.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Sass Variables in CSS calc() Functions</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>The most common use cases for variables in Sass allow you to drop variables directly into Sass stylesheets, so it’s easy to forget (or not to know in the first place) that there are certain circumstances where the interpolation syntax is necessary. The one I always forget is to use interpolation inside of CSS functions, like <code class="highlighter-rouge">calc()</code>.</p>

<p>The concept of ‘<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/String_interpolation">interpolation</a>’ just refers to the replacement of a placeholder with its literal value, so really in the case of processing Sass to CSS almost all of your references to variables are probably setting up an interpolation. That’s what’s happening when <code class="highlighter-rouge">color: $alertColor;</code> in your Sass gets changed to <code class="highlighter-rouge">color: #f00;</code> in your CSS output.</p>

<p>There are instances, however, in which the Sass preprocessor will not perform this substitution unless you <em>explicitly</em> specify interpolation using the <code class="highlighter-rouge">#{}</code> syntax. The <a href="http://sass-lang.com/documentation/file.SASS_REFERENCE.html#Interpolation_____">Sass documentation</a> explains that the interpolation syntax is necessary when using variables to construct selector and property names and may be used in property values except that it is only necessary in cases where operators next to it should be treated as plain CSS.</p>

<p>There is another case where the interpolation syntax is necessary, however, and it’s the one with which a recent (repeat) stumble inspired me to write up this note. Sass does not by default process the contents of CSS functions, so the line <code class="highlighter-rouge">min-height: calc($headerHeight - 2rem);</code> will be rendered to the CSS output with no change as <code class="highlighter-rouge">min-height: calc($headerHeight - 2rem);</code> (which is not valid CSS).</p>

<p>It is necessary to use interpolation explicitly to get the desire result in this case, so the correct line <code class="highlighter-rouge">min-height: calc(#{$headerHeight} - 2rem);</code> will produce CSS output such as <code class="highlighter-rouge">min-height: calc(50px - 2rem);</code> if the value of <code class="highlighter-rouge">$headerHeight</code> is <code class="highlighter-rouge">50px</code>.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 06:33:01 -0500</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/02/sass-interpolation.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/12/02/sass-interpolation.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Recent Reading: November 29, 2017</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    

    
        


  <div class="clear-block"></div>
  <h3>Books</h3>
  <ul class="reading-list">
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0812975243/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Rob Gifford. <i>China Road: A Journey Into the Future of a Rising Power</i>. New York: Random House, 2008.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>Rob Gifford had been an NPR China correspondent for years when he decided to follow Route 312, the transcontinental highway that travels west and north from Shanghai all the way to the border with Uzbekistan, as his farewell to China. <em>China Road</em> is his travelogue organized both chronologically and geographically as he follows the road and thematically as the different people he encounters provide him opportunities to explore the capitalist awakening in China, political repression, internal migration, the colonial and imperial history of China in Tibet and the Uighur territories, the tension between the improved material circumstances of low-income Chinese and accelerating inequality of opportunity, and many other subjects. Written in 2007, it is a particularly interesting read with the benefit of a decade of hindsight on some of the potential trends he identifies.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/938007671">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0812975243/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062645234/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Anthony Horowitz. <i>Magpie Murders</i>. New York: Harper Perennial, 2017.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>A double-whodunit that wraps a more modern thriller set in the London publishing industry wrapped around a Agatha Christie-esque English countryside cozy mystery. I would not be surprised if there were a lot of genre-insider stuff that I missed, but I was nonetheless impressed by the technical challenge posed by the structure and Horowitz’s success in pulling it off.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/995336235">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/0062645234/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1585675245/ref=nosim/latin031-20">P.G. Wodehouse. <i>Ring for Jeeves</i>. Woodstock, N.Y.: Overlook Press, 2004 [1953].</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p><em>Ring for Jeeves</em> has Jeeves on loan to the Earl of Rowcester while Bertie Wooster is away at a boarding school for young nobles to learn the basic life skills now necessary given the exigencies of the post-war welfare state. Rowcester’s own financial straits lead him to moonlight as a horse-racing bookmaker with Jeeves as his clerk. They are forced to welsh on a bet, and hilarity ensues through layers of escalating misunderstanding. Falls right in line with format and expectations, but fun stuff.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/55045280">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1585675245/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
      <li>
        <span class="citation">
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1616951117/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Helene Tursten. <i>Detective Inspector Huss</i>. Translated by Steven T. Murray. New York: Soho Press, 2003.</a>
      </span>

        
          <span class="note"><p>This is the first installment in a Swedish series of police procedurals set in Göteborg and written in the 1990s. The whodunit aspects of it were compelling and well-executed and there was enough suggestion of the socially- and politically-aware themes that crime fiction is can be so well-suited to exploring that I intend to continue. It was particularly interesting to read 90s Scandinavian angst over misogyny and white nationalism as the social context for a detective story from a late 2017 U.S. perspective.</p>
</span>
        <span class="links">
      <a href="http://worldcat.org/oclc/635706658">WorldCat &raquo;</a>
      <a href="http://www.amazon.com/exec/obidos/asin/1616951117/ref=nosim/latin031-20">Amazon &raquo;</a>
      </span>

      </li>
    
  </ul>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 10:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/29/recent-reading.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/29/recent-reading.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Explaining the Obvious</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>Be more explicit than you think is necessary, and you’ll nip misunderstandings in the bud. When everyone’s in the same room, it’s easier to notice an errant gesture that shows we’re not all on the same page. A remote team can only know what you say and type, so get everyone to agree that overexplaining won’t be taken as an insult. Don’t let it slip as the project goes on, either. “So what we’re saying is…” should be a common phrase throughout the life of the product.</p>

  <p>– <cite>Drew Bell on <a href="https://trackchanges.postlight.com/five-ways-to-maintain-a-strong-remote-product-team-5d430c164ddf">talking through the “obvious” on remote teams</a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 07:39:01 -0500</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/09/explain-the-obvious.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/09/explain-the-obvious.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Open a File in MultiMarkdown Composer from BBEdit</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <p>Sometimes I find myself doing more extensive writing in a Markdown file in BBEdit than I had anticipated and want to switch to a more focused environment. My preferred Markdown editing environment for longer writing sessions is MultiMarkdown Composer, so I’ve added an AppleScript to BBEdit’s scripts menu to open whatever file I’m currently working on in with that. The script follows and, as you will see, can be easily edited to work with any other text editor you prefer.</p>

<div class="language-applescript highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code><span class="k">tell</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nb">application</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"BBEdit"</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="k">set</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">markdownFile</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="k">to</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">file</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="k">of</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nb">front</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="na">window</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="k">end</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="k">tell</span><span class="w">

</span><span class="k">tell</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nb">application</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="s2">"MultiMarkdown Composer"</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="nb">open</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="nv">markdownFile</span><span class="w">
    </span><span class="nb">activate</span><span class="w">
</span><span class="k">end</span><span class="w"> </span><span class="k">tell</span><span class="w">
</span></code></pre></div></div>

<p>That’s it.</p>

<p>Save the file in <code class="highlighter-rouge">~/Library/Application Support/BBEdit/Scripts</code>. You can get to this folder from the Finder by holding the ‘Option’ key while selecting the ‘Go’ menu in order to expose the ‘Library’ item which is usually hidden. A new item with the name of whatever you’ve named your script file will now appear in BBEdit’s script menu (identified by the AppleScript paper scroll icon).</p>

<p>You can add another layer of convenience by adding a keyboard shortcut for this action using the ‘Keyboard’ pane in the System Preferences application. Having opened the ‘Keyboard’ pane, go to the ‘Shortcuts’ tab and select ‘App Shortcuts’ from the sidebar. Click the ‘+’ button below the list on the right side and select ‘BBEdit’ as the Application, type your menu’s title exactly as it appears in the application, and set your keyboard shortcut. I use <code class="highlighter-rouge">Shift+Cmd+M</code>.</p>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 11:46:01 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/02/multimarkdown-composer-from-bbedit.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/02/multimarkdown-composer-from-bbedit.html</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Athanasius Kircher’s Cat Piano</title>

<description>
    <![CDATA[
    <blockquote>
  <p>Not so long ago, in order to dispel the melancholy of some great prince, a noted and ingenious actor constructed an instrument such as this. He took live cats all of different sizes, and shut them up in a kind of box especially made for this business, so that their tails, stuck through the holes, were inserted tightly into certain channels. Under these he put keys fitted with the sharpest points instead of mallets. Then he arranged the cats tonally according to their different sizes, so that each key corresponded to the tail of one cat, and he put the instrument prepared for the relaxation of the prince in a suitable place. Then when it was played, it produced such music as the voices of cats can produce. For when the keys, depressed by the fingers of the organist, pricked the tails of the cats with their points, they, driven to a rage, with miserable voices, howling now low, now high, produced such music made of the voices of the cat as would move men to laughter and even arouse shrews to dance.</p>

  <p>– <cite>Athanasius Kircher in <em>Musurgia Universalis</em> (1650), as translated by Frederick Baron Crane, as printed on the insert in the last <a href="https://publicdomainreview.org/support/">postcard pack from <em>Public Domain Review</em></a></cite></p>
</blockquote>

    
    ]]>
</description>
<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 06:46:01 -0400</pubDate>
<link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/28/cat-piano.html</link>
<guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/28/cat-piano.html</guid>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>